<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <!-- 1 -->
      <result>
	      <id> https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks </id>
	      <rel>1</rel>
	      <text>
          All Fools' Day nt
          C'aayoti
          Ferry,
          At iho Canyon Ferry House). Iiepb by.
          our old friend Cnnt. StalTord. is wont lo
          meet occasionally tho Jolly bnrhelors of
          mo Hujaeeni mines, wuu sot nroumi lltu
          bnr.qunfl' their bovorog'cs nnil bewail lliclr
          sad and lonoly lives of bachelorhood.
          On Saturday evening, April 1st, whllo a
          party of thoso dUcousnlato chap wero
          engaged In Iho pastime mentioned. above,
          a spanking team was drivHti. to tho par
          lor door, by I. il. Tyler, ami by his side
          sat n blooming and buxom lemule, who
          wns politely, handed out of thu vehicle
          nnd shown to tho parlor. A buz of nil
          miration went up from tho crowd, nml
          Mn Tyler wns interviewed ns to tho pn
          ternlty and prdlgreo of tho lovely strnn
          gor. These Inquiries wero snttuflcd by
          thu stntntm nt that Mr. Stafford bail dls-
          chnruetl his ittnlo cook, anu tho truly was
          nn interesting widow, who lintl consen
          ted to superintend tho cuisine affairs of
          the household. Tho crowd otilotl v dron
          ped olf their cabins, donned their "bllr-d."
          shirts, shaved cl nu, nml dropped back
          to the hotel, ono after nitothar, each ono
          with it pnliiifntlng heart, nnd n quiet
          chuckle to lil'tisell that ha- was looking
          supremely smooth, and would recelrc
          tho first introduction nnd smiles of the
          widow. As they entered, Mr. Tyler
          led their, one by one nnd presented them
          to their fancied Idol, until the room wns
          crowded with rivals, Captain Stafford,
          wllh his eye on Iho knot-holo, tinted tho
          happy countenances of tho baeholors,
          nnd Iho witching smiles of tho widow,
          whllo Tyler did tho nmlnblc. Tho
          Judge of thu district, n happy, Jolly
          bachelor, but, unfortunately, very thin
          haired, borrowed n wig for tlio occnlon,
          nnd appeared befose thv widow, with
          his ours pinned back, nnd looking upon
          tho minors with tho lofty contempt
          which he felt bis position would give
          him over bis rivals lo tho lair willow's
          eyes. Tho guests having been all Intro
          duced, Joo Stnirer, finally summoned
          courngo to tako a sent by her sldo nml
          engaged her in conversation but what
          was his horror upon discovering tho
          fair female gently raised her whlto skirts
          nml shovo her hand Into tho pocket of n
          greasy pair of buckskin brcechos, which
          wero hidden by flowing garments, and
          from which she hauled n plug of tobac
          co, and pasFcd It to her admirer with a
          winning smile, nnd tho polite invitation
          of "Juo tuko n chaw Joo fell bnek iu
          amazement, nml exclaimed, "Buys, if
          this y'ar isn't Jim Fulsom iu pottlconts,
          I'm a cnyuso." The April fool sell wns
          then seen through, and Tyler had to
          bent n hasty retreat, whllo thu supposed
          widow niHilo her exit through tho bnek
          door nnil hroko for tlic bush lo cscnpo
          the wrnth of thu crowd. Tho Jtttlgo
          now hicks only thirteen hnlrs of being
          halt! headed, owing to the wrathful man
          ner iu which hn ran his lingers through
          bis thin locks, when ho learned that the
          lovely widow was none olhor than Jim
          Fulsnm, a smooth-faced miner, rigged
          out for tho occasion. Helena Gazette.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 2 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=april+pranks+fools</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          April Fool.
          The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
          aod as impossible to determine as the birth?
          day of the first fool who marred Nature's
          original design of intellectual Man. We
          trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
          its birth ba files research. We are forced to
          admit its existence, without being able to
          assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
          enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer?
          tainly carried its memory in all their con?
          quests. Its observance was long cherished
          among numer?os nations. Abandoned to
          the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
          refinement, Momus seems to revenge him?
          self by selecting the most elevated and dig?
          nified objects for bis practical jokes. Nor
          man, cor nation, nor things visible, nor
          things invisible can elude bis satire. Nature
          herself seems convulsed with his sly sport.
          Her groans over a fallen race turn into in?
          voluntary, hysterical laughter at the bidding
          of this giant Harlequin, on whose kingdom
          tbe Ban never sets.
          The most pathetic scenes provoke the
          wildest mirth. We see men of bonor and
          repaie taking advantage of National schemes
          to secare private emolument; dividends the
          only consideration, the divisor of no conse?
          quence. April Fool 1 Divisor of scheme,
          plus dividends, laughing at his dupes, and,
          thanking Heaven he is not like other men,
          proving bis integrity by tbe faith of his
          fr ?en dB. April Fool
          The rightful Government of Louisiana
          using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti?
          ling Kellogg platform striking the first
          blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
          Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
          sending representatives to the Union at
          large, convinced that her distress must be
          of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
          Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
          which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
          balance cac not be determined; giving a
          gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
          April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
          the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
          which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
          a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of j
          bowling it down. April Fool
          England's tories and whigs doing their
          best to destroy the ablest minister of the
          Crown on the question of the Irish Univer?
          sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
          "cummin" while neglecting the weightier j
          matters of tbe law. April Fool
          France with Thiers more iban king, shoot?
          ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la R?publique 1
          "A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
          April Fool
          Ukraine peasants revolting against an
          ?utocrat who owns half the Continent of
          Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
          br the mere chance of being discharged at
          heir masters' heads. April Fool
          Each nation convinced that "the Par lia
          "mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
          s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
          :ree. April Fool 1
          Each sect persuaded that the whole world
          viii soon have bat one Faith, and that Faith
          ta own especial creed. April Fool 1
          Honor, probity, patriotism, troth and
          rirtae sb/J! prove'a successful candidate
          tgaiost rampaot Vice. April Fool I
          All the world surging, restless, doped and
          laping, cries: April Fooll
          Deep calling onto deep in awfal sport-all
          .be waves and waterspouts shoaling in
          nocking derision April Fool I And men in
          childish rage and impotent wrath yell to
          ?ach other and the Universe at large: Toa
          ire-April Fool 1
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 3 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ON ALL FOOL'S BAT
          i
          Brainy Men Ten of First of April
          Fancies.
          Actor, Artist, BatlrUt, Lawyer, Preacher.
          Etc, All Have Something to bar
          About This, the Fool
          Catcher's Day.
          COPTBIOHi; 183 L
          H E stage is in
          Eomo measure
          responsible for
          All Fool's day.
          So the histo.
          rians tell us.
          They say it
          grew out of an
          old Easter
          miracle play in
          Irhich the sending of Christ from An
          bas to Caiaphas and from Pilot to
          Herod was the basis of the mediaeval
          Jramatist's plot. But I don't think
          Hie stage has stuck to its offspring.
          We actors are a serious lot of people,
          particularly the comedians among us,
          for paradoxical as it may seem, acting
          Is all work and no play, and conse
          quently Jack is a dull boy. We would
          "MSTEIt, TXEASE GIVE ME A IIFT. JTLI.
          TOU?"
          T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
          but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
          cause that would be rather cruel.
          I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
          of April 1, of course; still I always look
          carefully after my coat tails on that
          day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
          of those who are careless about their
          parraental caudals during the Feast of
          All Fools. The sight makes me feel
          quite a boy again, for we youngsters
          used to do that sort of thing in Phila
          delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
          It, too. I believe that some of the live
          lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
          and have vitality and energy enough
          left to laugh at the result, as a comio
          paragrapher would say.
          The most foolhardy of all the tricks
          which I can recall in connection with
          this carnival of jeering and nonsense
          Is one that I have never seen played
          Eince I was old enough to require two
          digits to express my age. A bag and
          two boys were the ingredients of the
          trick, and it never failed to 6core a
          great success on a quiet side street.
          One boy got into the bag and the other
          Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
          rest of the boys who were "in on the
          ground floor" were hiding in hallways
          and doors and behind trucks across
          the street. An innocent citizen came
          W sauntering along. The boy who had
          hold of the neck of the bag stopped
          him with a "Say, mister, please give
          toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
          izen usually acquiesced and took hold
          of the bag to land it on the youngster's
          shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
          his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
          kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
          tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
          or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
          with palpitating heart and hair on end.
          while all the boys across the street
          pursued him with a villainous chorus
          of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
          .your face and go to sclioU" or
          something to the same effect. It
          Talways seemed to me that the joke
          was really on the boy in the bag;
          he was sometimes dropped hastily
          and heavily and was hurtand occa
          sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
          him a thrashing besides for being too
          funny. But it was an effective trick.
          and often an old codger lingered in the
          shadow on the opposite pavement to
          witness and enjoy the sport. You have
          seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
          of pig iron over into tho next state
          Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
          IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
          Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
          bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
          tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
          self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
          though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
          than that of the man whoso blood was
          frozen in his heart by the unexpected
          scream emitted by the occupant of the
          bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
          stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
          Jonx Drew.
          fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
          It doesn't seem right that the firs
          flay of a month so full of pretty things
          j is April is should be inseparably con
          w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
          dilapidated pocketbooks with string
          in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
          ntable hats with bricks underneath
          them, long streamers hanging from
          l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
          rung by invisible hands, and all the
          other dear old pleasantries that we
          know by heart. And we should prob.
          ibly have had a society for the pre
          rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
          It were not for the pleasure that call
          aren gel out of them.
          When a certain boy of my acquaint-
          fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
          Informs me that somebody is waiting
          ft;' see me in the library, not for the
          world would I refuse to go downstairs
          and pretend extreme surprise at find
          ing nobody there. Nor would any
          thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
          cotton-filled piece of
          candy which is shortly after offered
          V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
          UlUiD O
          End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
          every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
          Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
          he could raise such a shout of laughter
          as easily and unfailingly.
          Apropos of this train of thought
          there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
          published some years since, which will
          perhaps bear transplanting here, and
          which I subjoin.
          Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
          "de bazoo" is suggested.
          If yer want a good joke on some ot
          yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
          Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
          April Fool day.
          Yer work it dis way:
          Suppose a man owes yer ten dollars
          and won't pay yen Go see him and
          ask him for it. He ses he ain't got it.
          Wipe de floor wid 'him and take all de
          cash in his pockets and when he kicks
          apologize and se.y yer didn't mean fer
          ter hurt him it'b April Tool, see? Den
          yer needn't pive him de money back,
          'cause he owe s it, yer see? Course yer
          don't want ter try de razoo on anyone
          not under yer size, see?
          Den yer kin pay off all yer old
          grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
          gry and ain't got no money walk inter
          de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
          and say it's April Fool, see, and run
          out widout payin' nothin'.
          Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
          razoo. Steve Erodie.
          TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
          I am abked for a sentiment concern
          ing April Fool's day and pause in the
          whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
          to say that in my opinion time is far
          too valuable and important a factor
          for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
          ing or senseless joking. The world,
          especially in these days, is in far too
          critical and dangerous a position, so
          cially and religiously, to allow of a
          man with average sense to saj' noth
          ing of those who have consecrated
          brains to indulge in any other than
          profitable and upright intercourse.
          It is a personal relief to me to feel
          that in our ranks seventeen hundred
          officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
          local workers will be pushing with
          might and main of soul an enterprise
          which upholds sincerity and the ne
          cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
          Ballington Booth.
          A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
          Before stating what jokes seem to
          me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
          S&-
          WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
          April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
          temptation to say that I think the
          spirit of the holiday itself hat always
          been singularly misunderstocd. The
          day is really to be deemed a pause in
          time's serious flight, when folly could
          with propriety travesty wisdom, and
          set the world smiling. As it is, the
          first of April has come to be deemed a
          nuisance, wheu its observance is not
          don away with entirely. April Fool's
          day is sadly in need of soue one to
          champion it and xestoi e it to its right
          ful place in the calendar. It is not
          simply the day on which the boys and
          girls may make fools of their elders
          with impunity. I suspect that there
          was a time when it was regarded
          rightly, far away as that time seems
          to us now. Then the old people put
          aside their serious looks and grew
          younger instead of older.
          If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
          surely April first is the feast day
          of the saircs. when thev can act on
          Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
          little folly with your wisdom."
          As for those jokes which seem to mi
          good and appropriate to the dav it
          should always be understood that the
          element of surprise is the essential
          thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
          bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
          would ba given up to a general hazing
          of everybody. The most successful of
          April Fool jokes would be to surprise
          one's friends by a change of character.
          What a rare joke it would be for the
          confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
          upon that niece of his who needs only
          a little money to marry the lad of her
          choice. If all the cranks would put
          rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
          it would be for the rest of us.
          This kind of joke can be carried out
          ad finitum and would never fail to bo
          successful. Let the tippler remain
          sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
          flint employer can have a lark with
          his clerk by granting that increase of
          salary that has been talked about so
          long. Let the clergyman I say it
          reverently preach a sermon only an
          hour long to-day instead of one of
          four hours' duration. I am convinced
          that the idea would meet with success.
          People too old for jokes on April
          Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
          heads can have their joke. The repro
          bate roue can go to church this morn
          ing and explain that it is all a joke on
          his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
          a good thing because it is so unusual
          with him that it would give him un
          pleasant prominence. But he can do
          it to-day and escape with the admis
          sion that it is his April fool joke. I
          am glad the day comes on Sunday this
          year. B. Gillax.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 4 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          "WASHINGTON, D. C., SUNDAY MORNING, MAliCII 29, 1S0G.
          LS THESE MORTALS
          AN
          DYLL
          APRL
          WHAT
          BE
          :,0
          lift
          I t
          I II i fc
          a.CE upon a time" in truUi,
          quite recently then.' were
          fomefislilliat were haul to be
          of greatdepth, hothas to t heir
          bailiwick and intelligence.
          One Would e-neso frnm llilc
          description that they were taw-fiMi, that
          Is, wise-saw fish, hut they were not. They
          were eimpij- hucKeru; yec mey knew It
          was April 1'ool'b Day.
          On tljat Fame
          day a man went
          Fooling the Fishes-Bait 3SSa J "J
          Without Hooks. sot him down on
          the wharf and let
          downhisliiicand
          bait. The water
          was clear and he
          could ee the
          6uckers blinking
          and winking at
          each other and
          rubbing their
          nuouts, against
          tlie tempting
          bait.
          "HeiliinkKhe's
          run up against
          the highland
          suckcr."mid fin
          ny No. 1 to. scaly
          No. and noo
          dle No. :t i early
          swallowed the
          bait at short
          range laughing
          at the sucker at
          the o'lier nil of
          the'ne. But he
          fWifdrifJitalong
          till the fun grew
          hot.imd (hen he
          Tilled his pipe
          and hauled up
          his line.
          Nov.h-'reisa
          moral 'nthisMo
          ry. Th'-re was
          no jojK in the
          merry li'-l.er-m
          a n s b a i r,
          wlui h goes to
          show that peo
          ple who .ue too
          wise to "Lite"
          very often get
          left. e en as the
          fish didn't know
          a good Uiing
          when it was in
          dubitably i n
          their line.
          And on that
          same day in the
          same generation,
          a spinster lady
          declined to ojX'ii
          a letter, good
          forthisdayonlv,
          no rain checks. Is
          sued, which letter
          con tninoda bona
          fide healed pro
          IKaltj,.Uheand MieMioukl tarry
          togetlier at Jeri
          cho, or an j place
          elM- where there
          was good tarry
          ing, swooning
          and crooning in
          the thick after
          noon iK-rfiimeof
          lot uracil orange
          blos.-om. And
          the next da j the
          died.
          Oil the 1st of
          April, la-t, a
          joung wieacre,
          who lives on
          New Ilauipclure
          aieuuc. received
          a letter ,y f.pe.
          cial im-sMMiger.
          It wab fcuper
          bcribedina plain
          round hand, and
          in the left-hand
          corner were the
          words "Pmate;
          marked down to
          10, former val
          ue &o." The
          letter was re
          turned to the
          writer, with the
          remark on the
          margin. "Don't
          need any spring
          clothes." The
          lot terrnerel j con
          tained a part
          Iiaynient of $20
          on a $30 -debt
          or honor" which
          accrued from
          lost borrowed
          chips
          So when the
          bride of only
          two Aprils tcle
          Kraphed to her
          husband In New
          i'ork from
          "Washington the
          thrilling mc-s-fiage.
          "Two ana
          all's well," lie re
          ceived it, "Two
          and all swell."
          He replied 'Had
          eight. -a j self and
          feel much swcll
          er." She ws a
          little -mrpi-ised,
          to be sure, and
          whei icy grow
          up she will tell
          the twins about
          the mind reading
          capaeu y cf a
          handsome clerk
          of the Oimis Of
          fice. These hlMorl
          calcaes are not
          ed by way of pre
          lude to i he slate
          ment rhat April
          Fools' Day Is
          again with us, or
          will be on "Wed
          nesday next. Af
          ter these i-ad ex
          amples of mind
          read mg, it will
          be only t tie more
          perplexing to
          discover the dif
          ference between
          looking the gift
          horse !u the
          mouth and the
          gift horse him
          self should lie
          gallop up to the
          door.
          One half of the
          world will begin
          on "Wednesday to,
          play pranks on
          Uie other half,
          and it is an in
          teresting day be
          cause we have
          only two such
          days on Uie cal
          endar, the other
          being Talentine
          Day. Election
          day Miotild. per
          haps, be added,
          buttoallofthem
          FaUier A braham
          undoubtedly re
          ferred when he
          got off the fa
          mous bit or phi
          losophy, "You
          can fool all of
          the people tome
          of Uie time, etc.,
          etc. otr.
          The misfortunes of the day are hke the
          premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
          are coming, but you can't prevent their
          arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
          at once, even If your mouth Is full of
          turtle soup, than to fight against the in
          evitable. It Is better even to take in
          the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
          Ef 55
          Vtr
          JEm)
          Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
          The Times for Next Wednesday.
          Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
          Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
          into Municipal and National Life
          TH SUMS
          uoke
          by
          v d y
          f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
          strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
          fiddle- to play out the score.
          It will probably be a bad d7 for king
          makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
          fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
          Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
          together the elect of the Warwlcka
          of this day and generation, fore
          most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
          C I ar krer
          "V.
          fffj VfLLET vairR
          STRlFHi iu v
          rti r SL. x pA.
          .,mn jr.r.
          iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
          Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
          Uie little stranger Into the street. There
          may be millions awaiting the long-lost
          heir before jou die.
          The compliments of the season are firstly
          due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
          Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
          will do a land-office business on April
          Fools' I)a They will be bitting at a Uel
          shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
          Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
          dialect.
          The Attorney for the District and the
          interpreter of the clastic law of the local
          Medcs and Persians Is called in and he is
          promised fine raiment and an amethystine
          ring ir he expounds the letters of fire on the
          wall. Kefer.'ncc to Uie snap shot of the oc
          casion will be found in the margin or tins
          page. Of course, tins maj not happen, but
          it ought to, which isa much better considera
          tion. There is one place in the United States
          where eerj thing can happen, proidcd
          always it is not something practical even
          will enforce the rules and order the gal
          leries to be cleared.
          Mr. Morrill of Maine Mr. President, I
          have lieen llfty jcars in the Senate in the
          ambassadorial capacity of a Senator from
          Maine, atrl I have ncer jet heard
          The Toreign Voice I am a talker my-f-clf.
          (Renewed applause from Uie gal
          leries.) The President The sergeant-ai-arms will
          arrest that obnoxious peiaonage.
          The galleries are cleared, and the ser-
          whlch to exclude the April Foots Day dis
          turbers of the White House peace.
          In the mind's ee, without even a warm
          application of the Roentgen ray, it is easy
          to see the fighters against follv seated at
          the table in what the President told the
          delegation of Baptist ministers was his
          "workshop." Ip a certain sense, tin-, is
          true, because It is there lie saws wood. The
          President casts aside carefully all tlie
          suspected letters and puts all the packagi-v
          Iu a tub of water near him on the floor
          to kill the microbes and anymcidental dyna
          mite. The morning is passed away pleas
          antly, and he asks for a cigar.
          "What kind, extellenzaZ" queries F. A.
          H in one-third Spau'sn and two-thirtls
          Iiayard.
          "A Duke of Veragua," replies excellenza.
          and Fie-Tt!oi!sard-DolIars-a-Year in the
          future opens a new Ijok. The rest of this
          story is done in black and white pictonally
          on this Seventeenth Page. In scene the sec
          ond the unfortunate bot-opener la on his
          tr
          iiiiinwifi ll'ir i5j
          4m
          April 1 at the District Building:.
          A Neat Little April Eiiect in the Senate.
          a Joke. To guess the name of that place
          is not as hard as guessing the number of
          five black beans in a transparent jar. It
          is the United States Senate,
          In the afternoon of "Wednesday next,
          after the morning hour, the Cutian olla
          podrida will be in full blast. Senator
          Lodge will hae spoken on the letter that
          never came to Secretary Olney, Senator
          Mills will hae taken Cuba "vi et aimls,"
          and Senator Hale will have delivered his
          accustomed eulogy on the late Don Canovas
          de Quixote. The listening Senate ib suddenly
          startled by a thin foreign voice, which
          says, "I'm something of a talker mjself."
          Applause breaks out in the galleries.
          The President of the benatc-If these
          demonstrations are repeated the President
          vtw n
          A Joke on the Republican RiBg-sters
          geantr.it-arms and Firsts Assistant Stewart
          rush up into the peanut' reservation. They
          return and report that the miscreant has
          escaped.
          The Presldent-The Senate "will be In
          order.
          Mr. Chandler As I was saying, Mr.
          President, I
          The Torclgn Voice I am something of a
          talker mjself.
          Nothing could exceed -the commoUon in
          the Senate when its courtesy was thus sat
          upon and spat upon by this intruder. It
          was the eagle eje of Senator Sherman
          of "Our Foreign Relations" Committee
          that discovered the intruder, winch was
          quietly looking askance at the President
          out of its white-winged eye, a beautiful
          queen red and gold parrot direct from Bar
          celona. "It Is a Spanish spy," declared Mr.
          Lodge.
          "It should be shot at drum head," as
          severated the fiery Tennessean.
          "Try it from the clock," said Mr. Mills.
          "Willi the Presidential gun," added Mr.
          Hill of New 1'ork. i
          Suggestions, however, do not kill birds
          at long range, and. the pages were on the
          qui vive of excitement lo be let loose on
          the most consistent talker at that moment
          In the Senate. They were eager for the
          bird to fly down and light on tlie bald head
          of some Senator, like the eaglathat alighted
          on the head of the husband of Tanaquii.
          But the spy did not move, keeping his
          sinister eye on the Vice President, and
          evidently getting ready to sing his unwel
          come song again.
          Mr. Lodge Eutcka, lMr. President: Per
          scalam ad avem.
          The President Gqod; has the scrgeant-at-arms
          a ladder about him?
          The sergeant-at-arms at -once procured
          Uie ladder on which he climbed into office,
          placed it up against the lintels of the' east
          door, and reached for ithe parrot, which
          was seated on the Senatorial clock a la
          Poc's raven.
          Did the sergeant-at-arms land the bird?
          Not on your negative. The bird had a
          string tied to him and. he'-was hauled aver
          the parapet, and tle small boy at the oUicr,
          end of the string simply hauled In the fes-'
          the Spaniard, opened a -gallery door and
          went down stairiand .filled himself full of
          apple pic.
          This may not happen.but It ought to. A
          son of one or the surviiors of the Ford's
          Theater disaster would be tlie logical perpe
          trator of this lecfure by the pariot to the
          Senate.
          Too mucU .sympathy cannot be -wasted be
          tween now and "Wcdnesdaj'onthefeeilngs of
          the Chief Magistrate "with respect to his
          mail and exprc packages on the day -we
          celebrate. Thcrofhavc plrendj' been con
          ferences between him anci Fldus Achates
          Henrlcus Tiberius on taii; beet manner in. I
          rjtt&n.
          knees ascrvatmg in shattered sentences to
          the accusation or the Potentate of the Poto
          mac that he smelt treason in the tainted
          gale.
          "if third term doesn't go, lese mnjeste
          doe-." thunders the man of destiny.
          "1 know it doe?, Your Majesty, but by
          the saber of my father I knov not who is
          the nuereant, unless it be some godless
          member of the 1. W. X. M. of the Occi
          dental provinces."
          "And who are they, caitiff?"
          l-eonie who Need Missionaries, Ex
          cellcnza." "Then, bj- mj- halidom, they shall have
          Uiem galore before the ides or April."
          And with that His Mijestj-seized bis tab
          lets and wrote deep in the wax"'Colorado."
          "North Dakota," "Oklahoma," "Stew-
          til
          r
          Somebody's Little Joke en Groyer.
          Little Willie's OrieinaJ
          Idea.
          U (!L
          ''r
          T'&ryS "U
          misfortune "vr K7 ""7 JaB
          trying to J "M
          doiitwheth- X Nr"V 1 H
          there's a V A V l
          -"vvr-' "rv.-oB
          A-N1
          sV: V-
          J
          f
          .r
          They are not
          afraid of any
          sword of Da
          mocles.orknlfc up the sleeve
          of Crofcer. or
          any other gift
          of the Greeks.
          But they didn't
          reckon on tie
          .'deus ex ma
          chiua" of a
          Philadelphia
          hotel.
          With a rattle
          of tfti plates
          and a creaking
          of woolen cord
          a g e, down
          comes Mr. Mc-Kinlej-.
          stuffed
          full of the
          "looks that
          way," and the
          reast and fun
          go out with the
          lights and
          that Is noioke.
          The tevsons
          of April Fool's
          Day are many
          and valuablelf
          studied practl-callj-.
          A man
          stiouM not let
          his hcue burn
          down becaus",
          wiseinhisown
          conceit, I s
          neighbor telLs
          him that r.ts
          house is on fre.
          At the farce
          tirnr, if all tl e
          night caps and
          nightdresses in
          Paradise allej
          are sprinkled
          from the hose
          of the small
          boy on the roof
          who has been
          paid to sLai.t
          "fire," It enly
          goes to show
          that there is a
          certain degree
          of
          in
          fin i
          lire in your
          own house by
          looking out of L.
          the window.
          The place to r.
          look is in the ir3-'
          bamcnt, or
          any other In-sidepreclnct-Again
          the
          nan who pas
          s wisely bj- a
          silver dollar on
          the pavement
          feels had when
          he looks back J JCTI-i' J
          and sees that r
          another man 4 t
          has parted it up
          safely. If it's a
          iweketbook the
          eae is all t'ic
          sadder. Or. If
          the man w.'.o
          believes that ic
          is better t fa'ce
          in the baby off
          the d. orst p,
          takes itardtelL,
          hKi wife al.ut
          it, maj- r pcu
          the bundle to
          find in itc ncof
          ouroldfriTiis,
          the rag labj.
          So, agam. the
          bnckinthehat
          Is inevitable,
          but it Is no use
          to go home in
          that condition.
          It. of coarse,
          requires a good
          deal of forti
          tude and saw
          teeth to eat a
          cotton batting
          dumpling, or to
          chew, with a
          scriptural face
          even a small
          piece of candy
          with a j-anvin-side,
          but it is
          said that It ha3
          been done rath
          er than ac
          knowledge the
          joke, but in "r
          nearlv all nf
          Uie instances
          Uie patients
          died as mar
          tyrs, like the
          Who let: the Z. T
          foc eat. nut of 'wil
          his breadbas
          ket rather thnn
          be indicted for I f
          dealing the
          fox. I I
          If you find
          It yarn or cot
          ton, spit n c ut i ?sgss3
          iiiuii. i is vt -5;,
          Reach for all I t?it'i SS
          the nunev in
          sight, ric up
          all the pot'et
          books, open all
          jour icttcrs,
          receive all the
          visitors in or
          out of myster
          ious lirdles,
          foronth.s par
          ticular da it's
          the only way
          to i o e t h.e
          problemsof the
          other fool. It
          Is somewhat
          strange that a
          person wl o be
          lies esat it is
          theucexrcctcd
          that always
          happens.scoms
          to look behind
          him when a
          small boj- jay
          to him confi
          dentially: "Mis
          ter, jour lorse
          hasdroppedhis
          tail." it is
          human nature
          to look back
          when he has
          turned the cor
          ner. There have
          beenverymnny
          8age tomes
          written about
          the origin and n HfTTT f
          uses of April ,h; rrh7-
          Fool's Day.
          Som writers
          ascribe to it a
          Roman, and
          others a Greek
          origin, it is
          more than likely that It began on the day
          when Esau tried to pas himself off for
          Isaac with their bliud parent. Abraham.
          Atu.ia.tia, i.onutr, dtetovrtl tUat the
          kLii.iI okC-r lad hair en hi brain and.
          tho t o-n. of Esau was launched for all
          the rget. They have had hairs on their
          brains cer since.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          APRIL CALLED
          OUT ALL ITS
          ARMY OF FOOLS
          The Jester and Victim
          Alike Make Merry.
          THE MORGUE'S BUSY DAY
          McENERNEY AND HIS COUN
          TERFEIT PRESENTMENT.
          Sad Tale of the Dentist Apprentice
          and the Soubrette Who Could
          Not Find the Key to the
          Curtain.
          April dawned bright and beaming and
          kept merry throughout its. first day
          blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
          fools look alike to me."
          In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
          and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
          a landmark of the past, the jester was
          out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
          galore.
          The fun began early and lasted late.
          A very few new jokes were perpetrated
          and all the old ones revived, while the
          usual good humor of both jester and vic
          tim prevailed during the entire day. The
          email boy was not so much in evidence
          ;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
          eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
          duous duties of trying on new suits and
          boots and hats, drove for once all
          thoughts of mischief from the mind of
          the budding lords of creation. The offi
          cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
          victims to the merriment- of the day.
          When the day was but a half hour old
          —at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
          sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
          pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
          charge of a body at the Hobson House.
          "Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
          quickly to the place, only to find that
          April had dawned and that some one un
          known wa? taking liberties with dignified
          city officials.
          In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
          Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
          fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
          -ceasingly from early morning until mid
          i night and all sorts of messages were
          voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
          also employes this method of fooling un
          suspecting friends.
          Tiner-aling-iing.
          "Hello! Well—"
          "Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
          Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
          Call him up— No. 1947."
          •'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
          "No: this is the Morgue."
          A bang— that's Mary's telephone— a
          enwe— that is the Morgue.
          While people were having fun at the
          expense of the city the' city was enjoying
          Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
          ing the prank over and over a^aln and
          hailing each new victim with shouts of
          applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
          At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
          Third streets at regular intervals a box,
          neatly packed and stamped, as though
          rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
          less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
          a man, woman and child, representing all
          sorts and conditions of society, stooped
          to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
          None got any farther than the attempt.
          The shouts of the crowd, many of them
          previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
          off, and he hastily lost himself in the
          throng and waited in his turn for some
          one to laugh at.
          It was both a costly and hair-raising
          April fool experience that Walter Mosier
          had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
          an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
          ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
          tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
          him to putter around the molars of his
          customers who are out of funds.
          One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
          Mosier was delegated to perform the
          charity service. The, victim was a boy
          about 12 years of age. He was suffering
          from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
          cided that the nerve must be killed, so
          forthwith he filled the cavity in the
          troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
          to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
          youth home happy.
          When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
          the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
          his employer of his charity work. Then
          Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.
          "Say, Mosier." said the dentist, with a
          serious look on his features. "I've just
          received a telephone message to the ef
          fect that the arsenic came out of that
          boy's tooth and he swallowed it."
          "My God!" exclaimed, the would-be
          dentist. lf ls he going to die?"
          "Well, the doctors are working on him
          now, but they don't think they can save
          his life."
          "Say. Doc, I'm going to get out of town
          before this kid dies. I don't want to get
          pinched."
          "Well." said Dr. Perkins, with a merry
          little twinkle in his eye. "You can suit
          yourself about that, but I'd advise you to
          stay here. They-can't do any more than
          charge you with mupder."
          "Murder! Ugh! Don't say that. Dr.
          Perkins," retorted Mosier, tearfully. "I
          didn't mean to do It. I'll go and take
          some arsenic myself."
          The crestfallen apprentice spent several
          moments of contrition and then he made
          up his mind to get out of town. He got
          50 cents from Perkins and made haste to
          the nearest barber-shop, where he Invest
          ed it in a haircut and a Bhave. M osier
          gave the tonsorial artist orders to cut
          }-is hair to the scalp and Bhave his sprout
          ing mustache entirely off, hoping thereby
          m disguise himself. The badly frightened
          youth then returned to the office to learn
          further detnils of his mythical victim's
          condition. Dr. Simpson told him th« boy
          was worse and Mosfer. started to leave the
          office. "Wait a minute." called Perkins.
          "Where are you going?'
          "God knows where I'll go, but I'll never
          go to jail for poisoning- that kid," an
          swered the youth.
          "You go down to the ferry to-morrow
          and if the boy dies I'll telephone to you,"
          suggested the doctor.
          Mosier slipped out to his mother's
          home, borrowed 510 and as early as 1
          o'clock yesterday morning he arrived
          at the ferry thoroughly disguised to
          avoid possible detection. He walked up
          and down the cheerless and 'desolate
          wharves till morning, and then not hear
          ing anything from Dr. Perkins bought a
          ticket for Sacramento and stole aboard
          the boat like a skulking criminal. On
          the train he acted for all the world like
          a noted forger crossing the line to Can
          ada.
          ttosiec confided to a friend before he
          left that he would commit BUicide rather
          than go to jail, which knowledge tuning
          to Dr. Perkins made him decide noi to
          cfrty the Josh any further. A message
          was sent to the frightened youth, and
          he returned to the city. Last night he
          set about to drown his troubles in the
          flowing bowl.
          Garret McEnerney fell a victim to a
          deeply laid April Fool plot laid for him
          by his "close up" friend Jim O'Brien..
          The bulky and brainy man of the law
          dropped into O'Briens office, commonly
          termed the "Cabinet," yesterday noon to
          engage the contractor in a little chat.
          "Say. Garret." chipped in O'Brien in
          an innocent fashion just when the law
          yer was i-xplaining to Jim Nealon the
          way to make money, "when did you
          stand for that bust over in the Palace?"
          "What bust?" queried Mr. McEnerney.
          "Why. the file they put in the corridor
          of the Palace Hotel this morning," said
          O'Brien as seriously as if he was talking
          business with a moneyed man who want
          ed- to spend a "thou or two" in street
          work.
          "There must be some mistake?" said
          McEnerney. "No sculptor ever chiseled
          me."
          O'Brien is "close up," and his words
          had weight with the man who was so
          busy dissolving -the injunction against
          Chief Lees that he did not stop to think
          of April Fool's day.
          "Let's go over, Jim, and take a look at
          it," said MeEnernty, and .they both start
          ed out tho door. O'Brien had no inten
          tion of going over with his friend to seek
          What he knew to be a myth, so he con
          trived to' be excused In a manner that
          would not breed suspicion.
          The opportunity presented itself when
          Judge Lawlor happened along.
          "I'm going to take the Judge on -for a
          minute," said O'Brien. "You go over and
          look at that yourself and I'll wait for
          you."
          Off went Mr. McEnerney and his April
          Fool went down on the arc.hives of the
          "Cabnit" as a decided success. Every.
          body who dropped into the Cabinet was
          sent over to the Palace Hotel to see what
          McEnernev had looked for in vain.
          "Pete" Dtinworth. the well-known vo
          calist, was- the victim of a ghastly April
          Fool josh. One of his friends telephoned
          to Dunworth's house early yesterday
          morning and informed him that an inti
          mate friend had died the night before
          and was to be buried immediately.
          "They, want you to be a pallbearer,
          Pete," said th-e wily person at the other
          end of the line.
          "All right." said the popular tenor, af
          ter expressing genuine regret over tae
          unexpected death of his friend.
          Promptly at 1 o'clock Dunworth, ar
          rayed in a black cutaway suit and white
          gloves, arrived at the .undertaking par
          lors from which the supposed dead friend
          was to have been buried.
          "Is this where Mr. So and So Is to be
          buried from." asked Dunworth, giving
          the undertaker the friend's name and ad
          dress.
          "Why, he 1b not dead," said the under
          taker, "who knew the man very well. "I
          just ?aw him "at the corner of Sixth and
          Mission."
          At the Alcazar they revived the old the
          atrical joke of the "key of the curtain"
          with marked success. Mrs. Willie Dun
          phy, the latest addition to the company,
          ten minute* before curtain raising at thp
          matinee, was sent on a hunt for the "key
          to the curtain." "We can't open up."
          said Stage Manager Bryant. "We have
          lost the key to the curtain." Mrs. Dun
          phy. who glitters on the bills as Miss
          Howard, searched high and low for the
          key and was in a condition bordering on
          hVfiterics when the last bars of the or
          chestra died away and the curtain was
          lifted without a key.
          Ocean Water Tub Baths.
          101 Seventh st., corner Mission. Bait water,
          direct from orean.
          Advances made on furniture and .pianos, with
          or without removal. J. Noonan, 1017-102SMl9slon.
          W. S. MASON LAID
          IN HIS ETERNAL
          RESTING PLACE
          Buried With Masonic
          Ceremonies.
          SOLEMN FUNERAL SERVICES
          INTERMENT UNDER AUSPICES
          OF KNIGHTS TEMPLAR.
          A Large Delegation of Portland Offi
          cials and Many Local Friends
          Attend the Last Sad
          Rites.
          With the solemn ritual of the Masonic
          burial services the remains of William
          S. Mason, late Mayor of Portland, were
          interred yesterday In the Masonic Ceme
          tery of this city. The funeral ceremonies
          were performed' under the auspices of
          Golden Gate Commandery No. 16, at
          Golden Gate Hall on Sutter street.
          The mourners were the widow of the de- 1
          ceased, a large delegation of officials ana
          friends from Portland and the Knights
          Templar of Golden Gate Commandery.
          Mrs. Mason, escorted- by Mr. S. Sussrhan
          of Portland and the mourners, occupied
          the central portion of the hall during the
          services. The full Masonic ritual was
          observed without any deviation from its
          original and impressive forms.
          After the mourners had been seated the
          prelate of the commandery. Rev. A. N.
          Carson, escorted by Eminent Commander
          Charles L. Patton, ascended the platform
          and conducted the services. Commander
          Pattern 'read the ritual which begins with
          "We are born but to die." ana he was
          followed by Prelate Carson, who read a
          prayer for the dead. The Temple Quartet
          then sang an appropriate hymn. Miss
          Susie Gambell or Portland, by the, spe
          cfal request of Mrs. iafion, rendered
          "Jesus, Lover of My Soul." At the com
          pletion of the ritual the Temple- Quartet
          sang another hymn, after which the
          friends and Knights took a last view of
          the remains..
          The pallbearers were: Captain Charles
          Nelson, TV. E. Mlghell, M. Ehrman. R. H.
          Lloyd, Mayor Phelan. Judge B. A. Bel
          cher and" Samuel Swift.
          Among those who attended the funeral
          were: S. Sussman'and wife. W. A. Cle
          land. W. D. Fenton. A. N. Gambell, F.
          Hackney, David Campbell, J. C. Jameson,
          George J. Cameron. F. TV. Hanson. H. A.
          Belding. J. C. Luckel. W. A. Storey and
          J. Roberts, all prominent i-n Portland pro
          fessional and political circles.
          From the hall the body was taken to
          the Masonic Cemetery, -where the cere
          monies were concluded by a prayer from
          the prelate, and the remains of TV. S. Ma.
          son laid in their eternal 'resting 1 place.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 6 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
          contributed more to the extermination of
          the heathen religion and its priests than
          all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
          though they were also freely employed.
          The continuance of customs— especially
          droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
          the masses— after the original cause of
          them has been removed. Is a very common
          occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
          firmly believed that "fooling" people on
          the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
          of the annual public ridiculing of the old
          Druid's and their superstitions.
          Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
          character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
          day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
          called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
          lished in London In 1659. "numerous
          Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
          Fools on the First of April. This is said
          to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
          sending ye dove out before ye water had
          abated, on ye first day of ye month which
          among ye Hebrews answers to our first
          of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
          this deliverance it was thought proper
          whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
          stance to punish them by sending them
          upon some fool's errand similar to- the
          Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
          was sent by ye patriarch."
          The French associate with the first of
          April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
          llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
          posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
          they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
          ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
          verbs," a most curious and delightful
          work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
          author, gives the following expiation
          of the origin of April Fool customs "The
          word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
          Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
          length of time has almost totall- defaced
          the original intention, which w^ as fol
          lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
          took place about this time o'the year,
          and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
          and forward to mock and't->rment him.
          1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
          phas to Pilate, from Pilate Herod and
          from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
          or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
          from thence, by which we send about
          from one place to anoO«r such persona
          aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
          cule."
          But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
          ain, France and our/own country that
          fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
          The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
          throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
          April fool la called elnen zam April
          shlcken." The same custom haa also been
          observed in India fr>m time immemorial.
          Late in March of hold a great celetratton which they call
          the Hull festival, of which the last day
          is the greatest aid most general holiday.
          During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
          of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
          on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
          end In disapr^ ntment anat the expend of the person sent.
          But the cistom of making April fools
          has-been traced back to an antiquity even
          greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
          the Hind 9 Tne ancient Persians wer»
          accustorr«vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
          as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
          elaborv*the Utter the chief was the making of
          fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
          mate them on April Fools* day.
          jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
          tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
          i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
          .ay is thus alluded to:
          Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
          Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
          halts.
          "While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
          loose,
          Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
          "Goose."
          In England, from earliest times, th»
          ridiculous errands upon which the victim
          of an April fool Joke sent have been
          called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
          and true significance of this term ar»
          completely buried in oblivion and no an
          tiquary has yet been able to unearth
          them. These errands are as numerous as
          they are Ingenious. Some of them hava
          almost become classics, such, for Instance.
          as sending a person to a book store for
          the second edition of "Cock Robin" or
          the "History of Eve's Mother": sending
          some one to a milk dealer for a pint ot
          pigeon's milk and to, a shoemaker for an
          ounce of strap oil. which, if the shoe
          maker has been Initiated Into the Joke,
          the Inquirer receives In the shape of a
          severe blow from a strap acros3 the shoul
          ders. AMY F. STOCKTON.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 7 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          LOST
          In Antiquity of
          Ages.
          April Fool Kept by All
          People.
          Gigantic Hoax Was a Complete
          Success.
          "This Is the first of April,
          Hunt the gowk another mile."
          From time itruneiuorlal thollrstof
          April has been celebrated by all sorts of
          hoaxes and playing of pranks. Tho
          truo origin of April' Fool Is burled lu
          tho dust of centuries and our great
          est antiquaries seem unable to throw
          any light on tho subject. Nearly all
          people however, celebrate this day or
          its equivalent and the similarity of
          the practice and tho coincidence of
          dutes establishes without n doubt In
          the minds of authorities ihe fact that
          It had an early nnd common origin
          among mankind.
          Nearly all tho peoples on the Conti
          nent celebrate April Fool with pranks
          and tricks, and even the Hindoos havo
          a festival on tho 31st of March, called
          Hull, which coincides vjlth our April
          Fool.
          Ono of the most popular amusements
          on April 1, or All Fools day, as it Is
          called, Is tho Rending of persons on
          fruitless frrands. Unsophisticated
          persons are sent to tho bookstores for
          a copy of the "History of Eve's Grand,
          mother," or to the chemist's shop for
          "pigeon's milk," while small boys arc
          sometimes sent to the harness shop for
          strap oil, when a liberal dose of this
          treatment Is usually administered to
          the boy.
          There Is a story told to the effect
          that Francis, Duko of I,oiTaIne, mid
          his wife owed their escape from cap
          tivity at NanteH to this popular cus
          tom. Arrayed as peasants, they were
          makiug their way out. of the territory
          when they were discovered by a wo
          man who knew them. She Immediate
          ly hastened to a guard, and told him"
          that the Duko was escaping. "April
          Fool," said the guard laughingly,
          treating the matter as a joke, and
          while he laughed the prisoners made
          good tlieir escape
          Occasionally a gigantic hoax Is per
          petrated on tho people as a whole, and
          such a one met 'with groat success in
          London in I8RO. Some wag distributed
          cards, bearing an official looking seal,
          which read: "Tower of London Ad
          mit the bearer to vlorv the annual core,
          raony of the washing of the white lions
          on Sunday, Aprij, 1, 1800. It Is par
          ticularly requested that no gratuities
          be given to wardens or their assistants.
          Admitted only nt tho white gate."
          This trick was highly successful,
          and people swarmed to tho tower to
          view tho washing of tho whlto lions.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 8 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          APRIL FOOL HUNTERS ARE
          ON THE JOB TODAY
          "All Fools' Day."
          Just why the first of April |1§
          let apart as an occasion when
          very.; wag hoe "j license .to pra'otloa
          iewptlon on tils fellow
          man and get the laugh «n him no
          nne seems ,to know, bat the cus
          tom is gen©r«l and o* loss stand
          ln«.* And after all i ttia pranks ol
          the "April Fool H tinnt«rs s» gen
          smlly tharmless.
          PW t yoa I are not abta Ito langa
          when |g tfhe laugh Is Yon ni MM
          lc««p jrou* wtta WMIM to iflj
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 9 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
          The San Francisco
          SUNDAY
          CALL
          ¥*ar 9/% v /^L v^ B l^W v jl HUB MI vU
          Aprill Fool
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 10 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+foolls+prank</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          JOKERS ANNIHILATE ARMIES
          April-Fool Pranks Play Havoc With
          European "War Map.
          According io me map wmcu t-roi.
          U p Wrench has prepared and kept
          I
          In the corridor of the third floor of
          Academic Hall, European armies have
          made radical changes in their ma
          neuvers. The French apparently have
          given up the war and have fled to the
          western coast of France. The Eng
          lish have disappeared entirely. All
          the German forces of the western
          theater are quartered in Paris. In the
          east, the Austrian and German forces
          are massed in the lowlands of Prus
          sia, surrounded by Russian and Ser
          vian troops. A few Servians are left
          as garrisons along the frontier. One
          lone Austrian army corps has escaped
          and is now stationed in the middle of
          the North Sea.
          The havoc Is attributed to some
          April Fool prank.
          Another Instance of April Fool
          thoughtfulness was shown this morn
          ing when a member of the Agricul
          tural faculty phoned to the county
          jail asking "who had left a call for
          him."
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-halloween/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <!-- 1 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014760/1861-10-31/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Halloween+Hallow+Hallowmas</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
           Alt Hallow Ke.
          To-night Is it!) IUItoto Tee, or Hallow n'en,
          as being tlie vigil or ove uf Ml Hallow Day
          Tbe Jlomlsh Church designed this day to bo
          held In boner nf all those taints who had not
          particular days appointed for them, but Ittloes
          not appear that All nallowD,iy,or Its eye, oro
          ever marked by very particular observance
          In the Cathollo ohurchj novertholess. there
          Is Boarooly any tlmo more distinguished by the
          common feoplo of many portions uf the Brlltsh
          Kinging of bells was one of tho modes of
          celebrating Hallowmas m tngiana in umos piuii.
          It whs a Itoman Oathn.lo practice, being da
          signed In aomo way to flvr the souls or de
          parted Christians. For this reason, Queon
          Elizabeth prohibited It. It was also A custom,
          a few centuries ago, to have a cake oaken on
          this eve for overy member of the family, ns a
          tout mass cake or soul cake. It was oomposod
          of natmeal, and seoded; and pasties and fur
          mety were Incidental to tho samo evening. In
          families of good condition, a quantity were
          hfllrnn unit ant nn on a board, liko tbe shew-
          bread In old pictures In tbo Bible, to bo given
          tp visiters, or distributed among the poor.
          Thero was a rhymo for tbe ocoaslon A soul
          cako a soul cake 1 Havo mercy on uu uuns
          Man snult lor a soul-oaks I" Poonle went from
          parish to parish o soulinj. as they oalled II,
          that Is, begklng In a kind of ohant for soul
          oakes, or anything to in ike them merry on this
          eve.
          Essentially oonnooted with all these oustom
          are thoso bettor known ones which Burns has
          so well and so faithfully described In his peem
          of Halloween.
          J.an I'll In twa wl1 tentlo ec,
          Wha 'twas ihe wadna tell,
          But this Is Ji ck and thli Is m,
          She says Into hersel';
          He b.eetod owre her, and she owre him,
          A ihey wad ne'er mlr part,
          Till fuITI ne started up the lum,
          And Jean hid e'eu tiir h'art
          To see't that night.
          Nuts, besides being thus used for divination,
          are crackod and eaten, and hence, In tho north
          of England, AH Hallow Evo Is often oalled A'ul
          crack Night. Apples are also extensively eaten,
          tMd nimunmnt nt fruit havlnc: nrobahlv some
          reforenoe to the heather, charaotor of the day,
          as that or thanksgiving rortne proauco oi uie
          aiann tha fortnn telllnc customs desorlbed
          by Burns, besides the above are for tho girls to
          pull stalks from a oorn-stallc, and ascertalii.lrom
          tho presence or absenoe of the top pickle, an
          Interesting point In their moral history for a
          sntitartr 'amain to co to a kiln, and throwing a
          blue clue Into the pot to wind It, expecting that
          era finished It will oe neia duos, wnen, oy id
          nuirim' who holds, a rcsuonse will ba obtalnod
          dlsoloslng the name or the future husband to
          eat an npple at a looking-glass, expecting to see
          a vision ot the future husband peeping ovor the
          shoulilor to sow liomp seea in uie yarn, say
          ing, Hemp soed,1 s.iw thee, hemp seed, Isaw
          thee, and her that Is to be my true love oome
          after me and draw thee," expeotlng that, on
          looking over the ahouldor, a vision will be ob
          tulncdof the future spouse In the act of pulling
          growrl hemp to win three weohta o' naetblng
          In tho baru, expeotlng to see a like vision to
          fathom a barley staok thrice, expecting at last
          n afflhnita vrnur mistress to dlnashlrt sloeve
          In a rivulet at the meeting point of the lands of
          three proprietors, ana men nargit oyiue ure
          tn iirr. triistlnf to see nuoh a visionary person
          come In ani turn the other side to pull sulks
          of dece.eed oabbages, blindfolded, without
          choice, and augur, from their stralghtnes or
          crookedness, the figure of tbo futuro spouse,
          r-nn. tnt. Aut-rn urninn (innra u lull iuui. luo
          fortune she will bring, and from the taste of
          the heart, her temper Anally, to set threo
          dishes on the door, one empty, one with oloan,
          and one with foul water, and oause the oompany
          to Bpproaoh them blindfolded and dip In a hand;
          when he wh' dips In the empty one is expected
          to remain unmarried, he who dips in tbe foul
          one to ratrry to a widow, and he who dips in
          tho clean one to marry a fem.ilo not hitherto
          married. The whole of these rites are as
          familiar io the Welch, Irish, and Northumbrian,
          as to the Ayrshire peasantry. Many of them
          are also praotlsed In Englandon St. John's Eve,
          t. uo.,1 nf Jtinn.
          Young Amerioa, however, has Invented a way
          or Its own ror mo ooservance ui ah uaiiuw iiio,
          u nrnminunt feature of which Is to go round
          from house to house, and pelt with oabbages,
          turnips, Ac, the luckless servant who may
          chance to come to the door.
          In tho Catbollo ohurones oi miscuy, to mor
          row, there win be services as on Buiday; and
          in 8t. Aloyslus ohuroh.oorner of II and North
          Capitol streets, thero will be a solemn requiem
          sung by tho choir at 71 P. M. Mad.im Ceollla
          Young Is again tbo prima donna In this choir.
          Saturday, tho 2d ot November, is All Soul's
          Pay, when tbo C.ithollo ohurohes ofTor prayers
          for all the faithful departed: and at lojo'olook,
          on that day, a solomii requiem mass, with lm
          nnoinir itaramAnlfli. in to bo offered In Mount
          Olivet Cemetery, for the'repose of the souls of
          all therein imerrca.

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 2 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84027008/1866-10-31/ed-1/?dl=page&amp;q=hallowe%27en+hallowe%27en&amp;sp=4&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.225%2C-0.353%2C1.034%2C1.034%2C0&amp;pdfPage=undefined</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          HALLOWE'EN*
          SOPHY LA??GHAM'S DIARY.
          MALDON HALL, October 27, 1846.- I
          We have been a week here to-day,
          and I have never once opeued ray
          diary. Thwe is a blank iu my book j
          from that day we left oar dear mo?
          ther and our quiet house, till this;
          div, October 27. lint ?ts L have made j
          a ti rm resolution to keep a faithful
          chronicle of this year, (which is now
          fast waxing to its close,) I must write
          retrospectively, recordiug the events
          which have fiiled the week omitted, j
          us well us T can, from memory.
          Our part in;;- from mamma was a
          sad one. We had never left her be?
          fore, and both Margery and 1 feared
          she would be very lonely without us.
          We did not, on that account, wish tr)
          accept Miss Laugham's invitation,
          but our mother though it best that
          we should she has always regretted
          that we knew so little of my fa?
          ther's family, which was an ancient
          and wealthy one. It was their fault
          that we did not.
          Because my father (the son of a
          younger son) was not rich, only pos?
          sessing th?? pay of au officer of the
          army; and because ho had married a
          country clergyman's daughter, with
          only a moderate dower, they scarcely
          took any notice of him, au occasional
          invitation for the shooting season
          even gradually growing less frequent,
          till it ceased.'
          Sir Jonathan Langham, his uncle,
          lived m great style at Maldon Hall,
          but after Iiis death the maiden heir?
          esses "withdrew altogether from the
          world, and saw no one, not even inti?
          mate frierais. We had forgotten their
          existence, when Miss Langhain's let?
          ter of invitation to ourselves recalled
          them to our memories. It was really
          :i very touching epistle, though sim?
          ply and coldly worded.
          In her advanced age, she had lost
          her sister, and shorly after Miss Au
          gusta's deutli, a singular mortality
          <*r- had deprived lier of the two nephews
          w ho were next in succession to the
          property. "She was alone," sue
          said, "'iii the world, and a yearning
          had come over her to see und make
          acquaintance with poor Frank Lang
          ham's children. Would my mother
          span? us to her for a few weeks?"'
          "Allow me, however," continued
          the writer, "to explain that it is not
          with any view as to the disposal of
          my fortune that I send this invita?
          tion. Unhappily (as I cannot for?
          bear thinking) my father's will dis?
          poses of it, after the death of his
          daughters, to the next male heir, and
          this heir now appears to be a young
          Irishman, very distantly related;
          though, by a pure descent, he is one
          of the family. He is to visit mc
          shortly."
          My mother was divided in her re?
          solution to let ns go by this part oj
          the letter. Miss Langham could no!
          ascribe our visit to any mercenary
          motive. We could not. incur by it j
          degrading suspicion-so we came ti
          Maldon.'
          It was a cold autumn twilight when
          we entered the park, and a feeling ot
          strange awe, a kind of misgiving ol
          approaching evil, stole over me as 1
          watched the old trees bowing theil
          heads solemnly towards us. as if ii
          token of a gloomy welcome. I shiver
          ed. Margery looked round at rn?
          and said, laughing, "Somebody i:
          walking over your grave."
          "A more poetical Arab reading o
          vsuch creeping of the flesh is. Um
          something evil is near us," I re
          plied.
          "Thanks, Sophy. I am the onb
          person near yon," she said, merrily
          "There! you shivered again. An
          yon cold?'
          "No!" said I, "but very m elan ch o
          ly. Es there not something s uhlen
          ing in this old place, whose ancien
          trees have sheltered so many of ou
          race, long since gone?"
          "Not to me," said bright Margery
          "I can but think what a splendid in
          beril.mee it- is, und how I wish Mis>
          Langham would leave it to me. Lis
          ten-there is a chime of church boils
          Ts it iu honor of our appearance a
          the ancestral hall, do you think?''
          "No," said I. "the ringers are oubj
          pract icing.
          '"You are a strange mixture td' th?
          common-place and sentimental. So
          phy,"'said Margery. "Do the bell.?
          say nothing to you?"
          ""Only, 'Sophy anc Margery gc
          home again,' to my ear. not bei nf
          such an agreeable hes ing as Whit
          tington's was," said I.
          Then Margery beg in an cager dis
          enssion about bells and their varied
          voices, and how people always fane;
          they ?lear in them whatever tile;
          wish; which subject continued till w<
          drove up to the hall door of Maldon
          lt isa noble old pile; and as wi
          stepped in the ancient indi am
          glanced at the pillars and arches, tin
          old armor and trophies of the chase
          I could not help liking to feel that i
          had been the home of my ancestors
          A butler, whose age' and appear
          ance were in good keeping with th
          dwi liing, ushered na into the gram
          library, lighted by a large glowinj
          tire, near which sat an old lady, win
          rose as we entered, ami, leaning o?
          an ivory stick, advanced to greet ns
          A very stately person isMissLang
          ham, of Maldon, and her manner i
          wonderfully courteous and gracions
          I can use no other words. She lei
          us to seats near tho lire, and begun
          conversation by inquiring after th
          health of our mother ?ind ?issnring ti
          that she fell, grateful to mamma fo
          permitting us to visit her.
          knew your father very inti
          match- in my youth," she saul.
          were cousins, you know, but time
          and theichanges o? tho world divided
          us. He was some years younger than
          myself, but he is gone first."
          She sighed deeply, and gazed for a
          moment into tho blazing fire, which
          cast a long flickering shadow ol' her?
          self against tin- wall. Then turning
          her gaze full upon us, she added, ad?
          dressing me, "You most resemble
          your father.*'
          "So mamma says,"' 1 replied;
          "Margery is exactly like our mother."
          Miss Langham looked earnestly at
          my .sister, and Margery blushed be?
          neath tho fixed gaze of Um ?dd lady.
          How beautiful my sister looked in
          fin warm fire-??ght. There are few
          girls as lovely ns Margery, and so
          Miss Langham must have thought,
          though she could not, of course, ex?
          press her admiration.
          "I have two rither guests beside
          yourselves," she added, after a pause.
          "The heir of Maldon, Mr. Cornelius
          O'Haliorau, and a Langham-though
          of a remote brauch. They are out
          shooting, but will he introduced to
          you at dinner. Perhaps uow you
          would like to go to your rooms, ami
          take ?ff your bonnets."
          We assented, ami were conducted
          by Miss Langham herself to two
          charming bed-rooms, opening en suite,
          with a small boudoir.
          "These three rooms are at your
          disposal," she said. "Shall I send my
          maid to you?"
          1 declined, wit li thanks, adding
          that we had no lady's muid ourselves,
          and could dress without assistance;
          "or, at. least," T added, "wc help
          each other."
          The old holy nodded approvingly,
          ami walked away.
          We unpacked ami prepared for
          dinner; but ever and anon between
          this occupation, 1 walked to the win?
          dow and looked out upon the park
          and the sent gray landscape beneath.
          A new charm wa- added to the latter
          in the near tower of a fine old church,
          which rose above the trees; yet tho
          feeliug of depression which had
          Steden over me on our entrance into
          the park deepened as I looked out
          on the heritage of my family, and I
          thought that after ali it was pleasantei
          to live in our mo! lier's cheerful cot?
          tage, und ga/.e upon our own bright
          dower-beds and green lawn, with it.
          one old oak, than on the gloomy am:
          suggestive grandeur of an ancient am"
          extensive park.
          I was glad when Margery called
          me to assist her in dressing, for bet
          light chat ami anxiety as to how om
          dresses would look, drew my thought.'
          to cheerful commonplaces.
          Very lovely Margery looked tha
          evening. I felt quite proud of tin
          admiration 3. could perceive she ex
          cited.
          Just before dinner, the two gen
          tlemot. guests were introduced to u
          by Miss Langham. Her companion
          I a pleasant, chatty person, and th
          rector, a rather pompons old gentle
          man, who could appreciate the pow
          ?.rs of the Maldon cooli so well tim
          he talked very little, were of on
          party. The n et or's silence was atone*
          for, however, by the ceaseless chatte
          !-I can call it nothing else-of Mi
          i O'Halloran. He is the most astound
          ing individual lever met. Tall, hand
          some and admirably dressed, he i
          nevertheless vulgar, rcs, the heir o
          I Mahlou would never be taken for
          gentleman, if one did not know hi
          hirth. He has a most unpleasan
          I brogue, and uses expressions whic
          ?ire quaint, hut which gives one th
          idea of being the sayings of the Ami
          rican peasantry. However, he is ev:
          i deiitly studying to acquire a goo
          j manner, ami I could not help ol
          j serving that he both watched an
          imitated Anthony Langham, who i
          I as distinguished-looking as a Lan?
          liam should be.
          I have learned since from Mn
          Moore-Miss Langham's co m pan io
          -that the old lady is sensible of th
          want of refinement ia her kinsmai
          and regrets the relationship. If li
          had not made Iiis appearance in til
          most unexpected way from Americs
          Maldon would h.iv.- descended to Mi
          Anthony Langham, as next ma!
          heir, and Miss Langham motin
          over the entail which was to take e
          feet alter tin: death of herself and In.
          sister. Still, she was too high-bre
          to let Mr. O'Halloran see tlmt li
          displeases or disgusts her, and I fane
          he even thinks himself a favorite.
          Mr. O'Halloran is much strm
          with Margery's beauty, and offers In
          the wildest homage, paying her con
          pliments so persona] as to be quit
          un pleasant. My sister blushes an
          looks indignant; but lie is stolid, ?ni
          cannot perceive timi he hasoffende<
          We do not seeagreat deal of him
          that is a comfort-as he is shootir
          all day about tho preserves, or rathe
          I fancy, talking to the game-keeper
          as Anthony says he is not agood sho
          Margery and J spend oar morninj
          in our little boudoir, for Miss Lan;
          lunn seos no one till luncheon then
          write our letters ?md do any little wot
          we may require. Girls who lmvo^-i
          maids and small wardrobes must u
          some skill and industry toappearlil
          ladies; and Margery has great tas
          ?md ingenuity, und can alter ribboi
          and re-arrange trimmings, till s!
          makes ono dress do the duty of tv
          or three.
          Lut these toilet details ?ne qui
          beneath the dignity of a diary, so 1
          me pass on lo something else.
          lt. is astonishing how fast mount
          "fions days mel; into each other ai
          leave no trace on the memory. lea
          not now recall and put in their rig
          places the little incidents, the sa
          nigs, doings, thoughts and feelings
          tho past week. So, adieu, neglected
          time! All the impression thou has
          left is just that I lore Miss Langham,
          like her comp; ton, detest the heir,
          and pity that c._rming young Lang?
          ham, who should have been the m?s?
          tet-of the old plac?. He is all that
          the lord of such a heritage ought to
          be-manly, courteous, gentle, kind
          and intelligent.
          Margery does not share my horror
          of O'Halloran. She began by laugh?
          ing at him; she now laughs with him,
          and actually declares that his eyes are I
          very fine, and that he is handsomer
          than Anthony Langham!
          If it were any other girl but Mar?
          gery, I should say she saw him through
          a golden glamour.
          OCTOBER 28.-Wo are to have a
          large party here on Hallowe'en, the
          :'.lsr. Miss Langham likes keeping
          up old customs, and we are to have
          all the weird rites of the charmed
          evening carried out.
          Site has presented Margery and me
          with new dresses for the occasion
          very pretty ones they are.
          My beautiful sister has evideutly
          won tho hearts of both our kinsmen.
          Anthony Langham loves her, I can
          see, though he is kept from her by
          the constant watchfulness of Mr.
          O'Halloran; so, to console himself,
          he takes refuge with me and admires
          her to me, and listens.to my sisterly
          praises with pleased smiles.
          Happy Margery! If she marries
          him, she will be truly fortunate. I
          told her so this evening, as we were
          dressing for dinner, but she only
          laughed and said:
          ..What, should we live on, Sophy?
          He has only his wits for dower."
          A nobler inheritance, in my mind,
          than Maldon itself.
          Ah! how the wind howls and moans
          through the trees. The night is full
          of noises. Surely I hoard a bolt
          opeued down stairs. If it, should be
          robbers!
          I have listened, for some time, with
          a beating heart, but there has been
          no repetition of the grating sound;
          it must have been my fancy or the
          v. ind.
          I will close my book, say my
          prayers and go to bed; it is silly to
          write so late, with my lire just out
          and my room gloomy from the feeble
          light of my candles. It makes me
          nervous and fanciful; so good night,
          my diary.
          NOVEMBER 1.-I resume my diary
          to-night, because I dare not enter in
          it, by day, the events of the past
          twenty-four hours. Margery might
          glance accidentally over my shoulder,
          or wonder what moved me so much,
          and ask questions impossible to an?
          swer.
          My hand shakes visibly as I write,
          Alas! I half regretted that my diarj
          was so barren of incident; that tin
          days were so monotonous and un
          marked by any landmarks of memory
          I have incident enough now to record
          to my sorrow.
          Hallowe'en came. A large party as
          sembledin lin' stately saloon, opene?
          for the first time in forty years. Wi
          had a grand dinner in the banquet
          ing-room, at which Miss Langhau
          did not preside, the rector taking he
          place; and. after dinner, we joinec
          her in the drawing-room, and began
          under her direction, the magic rite
          of the evening.
          We burned nuts together (bavin;
          named them first) and read a laugh
          ing augury from their explosion o
          quiet combustion. We felt (blind
          folded) for cups holding earth, watei
          emptiness, and one a pocket-pistol
          these symbols being prophetic of on
          future husbands' professions; an
          Mr. O'Halloran loudly exclaime
          against t he truth of the oracles, whe;
          Margery put her little hands into th
          empty basin, which foreboded singl
          li ft-.
          The fun of the evening moved eve
          Miss Langham to merry smiles.
          must have seemed as if a glimpse
          her youth had revisited her. Ourin
          a pause she said:
          '"There are some Hallowe'en ritt
          mure trying to the nerves than thesi
          sowing hemp-seed, for example."
          "What is that?" we asked, sima
          tatieously.
          "The lady who questions fate," si
          replied, "takes some hemp-seet
          goes, at midnight, to the chard
          yard, and sows it around the belfr;
          tower from whence peal themarriag.
          bells, ?iud says:
          Hemp-seeds, I saw yen;
          Hemp-seeds, I mow you;
          And he that shall marry mo,
          Come after me and harrow ye."
          We laughed, and O'Halloran (wi:
          had appeared to better ad vanta'
          under these livelier auspices) declare
          that he wished some of the ladi
          would try it.
          A universal exclamation of dislil
          to the experiment wat answering hir
          whet: a footman entered, and, a]
          proaehing Mr. O'Halloran, told hi
          that a person wished to speak to hi
          on imperative business.
          I fancied that O'Halle.ran change
          countenance a little, but he laugh?
          still, and hoping that somebody wou
          prove heroic and try the hemp-sec
          sowing, he left the room.
          The conversation continued on tl
          same subject; Miss Langham, wi!
          quiet humor, regretting that tl
          courage of the young ladies of tl
          nineteenth century was so much inf
          rior to that of the damsels of aneie
          times, tili, in playful daring, loden
          to sow hemp-seed myself. For a m
          ment, sin? hesitated," then she replie
          "So you shall, Sophy! Only,
          stipulate that you .shall wrap yours?
          in a large shawl, and sow your hem
          seed running, to keep yon warm. Ti
          church is so close at hand, and so pi
          vate, (shut into the grounds,) that
          there is no real cause for fear."
          "Surely you won't go. Miss Sophy?"
          was the general erv, and Mrs. Moore,
          approaching me. remonstrated in a
          low tone, saving that Miss Langham
          was a little childish on these points,
          and I had really better not go; but a
          sudden resolution possessed me to j
          undertake the adventure, and I per?
          sisted in it.
          About ten minutes or a ?plai ter to
          twelve, I left the hall, alone, wrapt in
          a heavy woolen shawl, which J drew
          over my head. T was followed by the
          good wishes and remonstrances of
          most of the guests, who escorted me
          to the door.
          It was a bright moonlight night,
          and my shadow was east on the gravel
          carriage-road almost as distinctly as
          in the sunshine. Tin' wind sighed
          mournfully through the trees, that
          waved their lai'ge arms above my
          head; and I confess, when I turned
          down the steps leading to the church?
          yard, a thrill of awe-T would not
          allow it to bc fear-passed through
          me.
          Everything 'A MS SO still and hushed,
          and tho tall shadow of the steeple fi ll
          so clearly on the ground in the solemn
          light, that I felt uneasy at. the idhi
          desecration of observing such a pagau
          rite on the holy ground.
          As I approached the church more
          closely, this feeling of reverential re?
          luctance to perform my foolish task
          increased. Alas! if I had only obeyed
          it! 1'ut it vas combated by thc fear
          of ridicule, and of the doubts my
          companions might feel as to my real
          motive for not completing my task,
          as well as by a reluctance, to cast im?
          plied blame ou so aged a lady as our
          kind hostess. So I took the basket
          in my hand, and scattered fae hemp
          seed, whispering the formula, as ran
          round t he tower.
          Suddenly I heard the sound of foot?
          steps. A superstitious fear, whicb
          was quite uncontrollable, seizt il me.
          I darted into an embrasure of t hc
          wall, and crouched breathless behind
          a large buttress.
          The next, moment, heard voicei
          as well as footsteps. They caine verj
          near, and paused close by my hiding
          place.
          "I tell you," said one voice, "it i:
          of no use to make a fool of yourself
          You must get the property ut once
          or you will be found out. Here's tin
          needlul dose, if von like to give it t<
          kerj;
          ??m>- repli d the voice of O'Hal
          l.ffjSr 'T can't She is vcr;
          olilr I will wait and see what wil
          come of it; if I am found out, wir
          even then we shall have a good booty
          We are sure of the plate, if we don'
          get the estates, "lint my belief is. w
          are all right, and shan't fail of success
          Having taken in the lawyer hitherto
          as well as Ih.e old woman, we have n
          real cause to fear at present; it's
          long way to Ameriky. and it's nothiu
          but your impatience to share tie- pr'
          perty that makes ,tm urge such hast?
          Uncle Ned."
          "Uncle Nedi'- The voice of th
          speaker thus named was that of a tal
          fine-looking footman, whom Mis
          Langham had engaged soon after h<
          sister's death, when she resumed lu
          long-interrupted intercourse with th
          world.
          "Well, you have heard what Joh
          Green said. He wouldn't have com
          down to-night to warn us for nothing
          Give her this dost?,'' continued th
          voice of the footman, ''amt you wi
          be master here by to-morrow."
          "I have said I won't, and I won't,
          replied O'Halloran, doggedly. "Yo
          may do it. yourself, if you ?ike; bi
          mind, I don't ?misent to it."
          The footman laughed, and said:
          "A precious bull that! but am ti
          old a bird to be took with chaff,
          ain't going to put my head in au 'alb
          for any one; but I advise- you io tal
          Jack's advice ?md warning. Now.
          must go; it's nigh upon supper-tim
          and I shall be missed."
          They moved on. The next minut
          O'Halloran's foot crushed somethin?
          quite audibly in the stillness.
          "Hilloa!" said he, with .1:1 oat!
          "what's this? Hemp-seed all abu
          the path!" Another oath. "Son
          of those confounded gals have bei
          strewing it, then! Can we have bet
          overheard?"
          "Nobody was here a minute or tv
          ago," replied Ned; "I looked behii
          every buttress before we be.em
          talk.'"
          "They may have como since. F<
          low the track of the seed sa
          O'Halloran.
          And they did follow it, with fat
          accuracy, and drew me, shiverii
          with fear and horror, from my bi
          ing-place.
          "Miss Sophy!" cried Uncle Ned,
          a tone of dismay. Then, with fen
          fid oaths, which even now ring
          my ears, he drew a large claspkni
          from his pocket. I saw the bim
          glitter in the moonlight. 1 shut n
          eyes, and thought a rapid prayer.
          "Ned," said O'Halloran, in a win
          per, "it won't do! Detection wou
          be certain. Go home and wait, f
          fear you should be missed; w
          take caro of the gal."
          Still swearing, Ned loosed h
          hold, but O'Halloran held my ot!;
          arm firmly.
          "Now, Miss Sophy," he said, as
          were left, alone, "you have learnt
          your fate, and 110 mistake. Lie yt
          "must, and that this instant, unie
          yon swear by all the saints in t!
          calendar that you will never tell
          word of what you've heard th
          blessed night to any human soul."
          I hesitated; surely death would 1
          preferable io even an ia volunta:
          participation in so terrible a fraud.
          But this heroic decision .lid not
          last. I could nob help pitying' my?
          self, just as it' it had been somebody
          else. The youri? life seemed more
          precious to me than the old iuherit-I
          ance of our race.
          I weighed (with the rapidity pf
          excited thought) m\ mother's and
          Margery's tears against tho wrong
          done to Anthony Langham. Besides,
          Uncle N'od evidently hand detec?
          tion. lt might come without my aid.
          Moreover, 1 am ashamed to con?
          fess it, 1 was dreadfully afraid of
          being murdered. Fear confused all
          my perception

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 3 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82003389/1868-11-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Hallow+ALL+HALLOW+EVE&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.536,-0.043,0.716,0.68,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ALL HALLOW EVE.
          The Sast of Octdber, the eve of All Saints I
          Day, has been for ages a timeof festivities,
          peculiar costumes and ceremonies, in the
          old countries, but of these there are few
          traces in our country. It is a season when
          fairies and wood-land elves come out in
          force, play pranks on passers by, dance
          merrily on the bill sides, and perform fa
          vors for those who have the good fortune
          to meet with them and fall into their good
          graces The weather had been very wet
          and disagreeable for some days, but on
          Saturday it cleared up cool and pleasant.
          SIn "the good old days" the young folks
          gathered in the evening to enjoy the plays
          and stories of the time. One legend di
          Srects the young girls who wish to know
          who their future husbands will be, to go
          to a grocery store and there steal a her
          B ring; taking it out of the brine it must be
          roasted without washing or cleaning, and
          e eaten up. They must then go backwards
          s to bed and drink no water. During the
          Snight the future partner of their joys will
          Sappear and offer them water from a clear
          running brook. Many a bonnie lass bas
          taken her supper of salted herring and
          gone to rest, to dream that she was laying
          Sin the shade of some favorite tree. with a
          Smurmuring brook close by, the cool waters
          of which were temptingly near her parched
          lips. yet be3yond the most frantic efforts to
          .reach it in her dreams. On this night
          they pull the Yarrow and sleep on it, the
          charm of which will bring them a vi.son
          of their sweet-heart. Going to the fields
          they pull nine blades of the plant, repeat
          ing at each:
          "All hail to the Yarrow, the wisest of
          flowers,
          SThon flairest of floweTrs to me,
          I tryete thee to tell io,, before morn
          Who my true lovec shall be."
          SThey then retire to rest and must speak
          no more until 'Ster they have slept. The
          following legend I believe has never been
          in print, ~althoughl it is quite current in
          C the north of Ireland, where it is believed
          by many to be true:
          wAsHING IN TRE DEVIL'S NA1t
          one Hallow eve night two young girls, liv
          ing on the coast of Ireland, nearthe Island
          Magee. went to a neighboring rivulet and
          Swasheditheir linen under garment in the
          r name of the Devil asking to be shown be.
          fore lorning their future husbands. Re
          tunrwiig to their rooms they spread the gar
          ments out to dry and each placed on the
          table a plate with bread and cheese for
          the expected visitors and then retired to
          bed. During the night they were awak
          ened by a most terrible storm, with vivial
          flashes of lightning, during one of which
          the shadow of a coffin moved through the
          room and stopped by the plate of the
          younger girl and immediately after a
          young man in sailor's clothes entered the
          room and going to the plate of the other
          cut some bread and cheese, and then dis
          appeared but left his sailor's knife on the al
          table. Before the year was out the young- of
          eat girl died, and soon after there was a
          storm and a ship wreck. One of the young
          sailors who was saved fell in love with the of
          other girl and they were married. Their ii
          union was blessed with a son, and while pi
          the wife was laying in bed, her husband
          asked for a knife to out some bread. She bi
          directed him to look in the cup-board. hi
          In Heaven's name, where did yon get
          this I" he asked holding up the sailor's w
          knife while his face was pale and colorless ki
          as death. After much urging she told him. bl
          How dare you do such a thing 1" he cried 01
          in a great rage that night we bada storm
          and I was washed overboard, and then suf- of
          fered the pains of the damned. No won- sa
          der I felt the flames of hell when you were s1
          working charms on me I" In his fury he a
          stabbed her with the knife and then left w
          the house and was seen no more. She re
          covered after a long illness and her son
          lived to be an old man. Some of his de- j
          cendants are said to be yet living in Coun- p
          ty Antrim. These are some of the quaint b
          customs and stories of Hallow Eve which b
          passing away brings as to,

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 4 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1891-10-31/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=spirits+All+children+Hallow+eve&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.028,0.03,0.956,0.908,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          All Hallow Even.
          The Bight When Maidens Try to Find Out
          Who Will Wed Them— A Curious Cir
          cumstance-Tricks Flayed.
          Written for The Morn*in*g Call
          All boys and girls know that October 31st
          is "All Hallow Even," though most of them
          corrupt its name to "Holly Eve." They
          know that it is a night of mirth and mys
          tery specially devoted to mischief, fun, in
          cantations,' divination charms and spells,
          but very few of them or their elders under
          stand its real significance or can tall whence
          it derives its name.
          It is many centuries since the Roman
          Church, finding it impossible, from the
          great aud constantly increasing multitude of
          the saints, to set apart a separate day for
          each one, decreed that November Ist should
          thenceforward be kept as a day in honor of
          all the saint!), and that It should bo known
          as All Hallow Mas, or All Saints' day, and
          that the night of October 31st, immediately
          preceding it, should thereafter be kept as a
          vigil aud known as All Hallow eve, th°se
          occasions beine still observed In the Cath
          olic, Episcopal and Lutheran churches.
          From its first origination Hallow eve has
          been invested with a peculiarly mystic
          character. It is an almost universal super
          stition that supernatural influences then
          have unusual power— that devils, witches
          and fairies are abroad; that all spirits are
          free to roam through space, and that the
          spiritual element in .ill livinglhum&nity can
          be detached from corporeal restraint and
          made to road its own future or to reveal to
          others what fate may have In store for them.
          As there is nothing in the church celebra
          tion of the ensuing day of All Sain's to
          justify these singular ideas and customs as
          sociated with Hallow eve, nnd an none of
          them are of a religious character, we may
          justly regard them as relics of pagan times.
          In all ages and countries Hallow eve has
          been dceiued. as it still Is, the occasion par
          excellence for devilling the answer to that
          momentous question which absorbs so laree
          a share of the thoughts of romantic young
          men and maidens, "who is to marry whom?"
          The means employed to gain this much de
          sired information are as quaint and curious
          as they are numerous and varied. For this
          purpose
          EVEBY TIME AND EVERY COUNTRY—
          Almost every district of every country— has
          had its own charms and spells peculiar to it
          self, and they lava furnished up almost in
          exhaustible theme to folk- poets and com
          pilers of folk-lore. Those of Scotland have
          been most graphically described by that
          greatest of all poets of the people, Itobert
          Burns. In his poem of "Halloween" ha
          has given us a most vivid account of more
          than half a score of Hallow eve charms
          and spells peculiar to the Scottish peasantry.
          In a very old book of folk-ore called "Vo
          True Arte To Keade Ye Future" 1 find the
          following: "If a maid would know ye
          name of ye man she is to marry, let her on
          All Hallow even steal out to a lime-kiln and
          throw therein a clue of blue yarn, still hold
          ing to ye other end. Piesentlv ye end In ye
          kiln will be sharuly pulled. Then ye maid
          must say 'who holds?' Whereupon ye voice
          of her future husband will pronounce his
          name both ye Christian and ye surname."'
          The only obstacle to the successful per
          formance of this spell is the difficulty of
          finding an old lime-kiln, but as lime-kilns
          will be In great demand among our young
          women when the important statement m ide
          in the above paragraph becomes generally
          known, aud us a demand for any article in
          this country is speedily met by an abundant
          supply, the number of lime-kilns will doubt
          less sunn be largely augment-, d, to the great
          delight of anxious match-making mammas
          and their dutiful offspring.
          Water, nuts and apples bear a prominent
          port in the spells and charms of Hallow
          eve. A quaint old book of charms, pub
          lished in Edinburgh in 1070, entitled: "Old
          Father Time's Bundle of Faggots Newly
          Bound Up," declares that an infallible
          means of getting a view of your future hus
          band or wife is to go to bed on Hallow eve
          with a glass of water, in which a small
          sliver of wood has been placed, standing on
          a table by your bedside. li: the night
          YOU WILL DItEAM OF FALLING
          From a bridge Into a river and of being
          rescued by your future wife or husband,
          whom you will see us distinctly as though
          viewed with waking eyes. This charm is
          thus alluded to by the English poet Gay:
          Last Hallow eve 1 loured my love to see,
          Ami [rid a spell to call tier up to me.
          With wI dreamed a dream and saw my own sweet bride.
          IniCOIIDectiOO with tills spell I am remind
          ed of a curious circumstance which came
          under my immediate observation. While
          visiting my younger brother in Newton,
          Mass., some year aij", my sister-in-law com
          plained at the breakfast table on the morn
          ing after Hallow eve that she had spent a
          most wretched night. On my inquiring tho
          cause she stated that she had hud a strange
          ly vivid and most singular dream, from
          which she had awakened with a feeling of
          the most distressing exhaustion. She
          dreamt that she was walking along the
          bank of a river, when a gentleman whose
          face she saw as plainly and distinctly as
          she had ever seen anything and whose
          features were indelibly imprinted upon her
          memory, fell from a bridge erected across
          the stream. Without a moment's hesita
          tion she plunged into the wat«r and after a
          desperate struggle succeeded iv bringing
          him ashore, whereupon she awoke feeling
          as much exhausted as if she bad actually
          passed through such a thrilling experience.
          In less than three mouths from that time
          my brother sickened and died. His young
          widow continued to reside in the same place
          with her two children. Four years later I
          again paid, her a visit, and while a guest at
          her house I learned that a bachelor Iriend
          of mine would be in the neighboring city
          of Boston on a certain date, and 1 tele
          graphed him to visit me at Newton. I met
          him at the railway station and drove him to
          my sister-in-law's residence.
          It was a beautiful summer evening, and
          looking from the carriage as we approached
          the house we Jaw her watering some
          flowers on the lawn. At sight of her my
          friend seemed so much agitated that 1
          anxiously Inquired the reason of his dis
          composure and asked if he had ever seen
          the lady before. He hud barely time to
          answer, "Yes, once, aud I will tell you all
          about it when 1 have an opportunity," be
          fore we had alighted and were in her pres
          ence. To my amazement she seemed quite
          as much discomposed as my Irietid had been.
          He subsequently told me that on the very
          Hallow eve when my sister-in-law had
          dreamed the dream above mentioned he had
          tried the spell of the glass of water and the
          sliver of wood recommended by my "Old
          Father Time's Bundle of Faagots," which 1
          had loaned him, and that ho had dreamed
          of falling off a bridge into a river, and of
          being rescued by the lady in whose house
          we then were, and whom he paw In his
          vision as distinctly as when he beheld her
          that night on the lawn. 1 also learned from
          my sister-in-law that my friend was the
          very man she had dreamed of rescuing on
          that same Hallow eve.
          The story of this most curious coinci
          dence, which is literally true, exactly as
          stated, is made complete by the fact that
          THIS FAIR OF DItEA.MKItS
          Were made man and wife before another
          Hallow eve.
          In a folk-lore book called "Ye Mysteries
          of Ye Wy.cnecraft," which Is the oldest in
          my collection, there is given a charm "by
          which a maid may know if ye man site
          loves be true." To perform this the maid
          Is directed to pluck, at midnight on All
          Hallow eve, two monthly roses with long
          stems naming one for herself aud the other
          for her lover, She must then go directly to
          her sleeping-room without speaking to any
          one and kneeling beside her bed must twine
          the stems of the two roses together and
          then repeat ihe following lines, meanwhile
          gazing intently upon the rose named for
          her lover:
          Twine, twine ail Intertwine,
          Let my love be wholly mine
          If In heart be kind and true.
          Deeper grow his rose's hue.
          IT If her swain be faithful the color of the
          rose representing him will grow darker and
          mure intense.
          Of all the many Hallow eve spells and
          charms associated wtth nuts, one of the old
          est is that which prevails in some of Eug
          laud'g northern counties), and which Is to
          the effect that if a young man or woman
          will go at midnight on Hallow eve to a
          Highest of all in Leavening Power. Latest U. S. Gov't Report.
          ABSOLUTELY PURE
          walnut tree and walk around it three times,
          crying each time: "Lot him (or her) that is
          to be my true love bring me some walnut*,"
          the future wile or l:u-tl>iind will be seen in
          the tree withering its fruit. The poet Gay
          thus refers iv his "Pastorals" to this cus
          tom:
          Last Hallow eve I souztit a walnut trie.
          In hopes my true love'a face that I might see.
          Three tune* I called, three times 1 waned apace,
          Then in the tree I saw my true love'a lace.
          A VEKY OLD HALLOW KVK DIVINATION,
          Formerly much practiced by English rustics
          to tell from what quarter of the compass
          the future husband or wife will come, i*
          performed by stealing out unobserved at
          midnight, plucking a small luck of hair
          from one's head and casting it to tlm breeze.
          Whatever direction it is blown toward is be
          lieved to be the location of the future
          matrimonial partner. This divination, is
          also mentioned by Gay in his "Pastorals,"
          as follows:
          I pluck this lock of hair from out my bead
          To ten whence comes the one that 1 shall v.cl:
          My. silken hair, fly alt the worm around.
          Until you reach the spot where my true love Is
          found.
          There can be no question that many of
          the observances of Hallow eve are derived
          from those of the old Koninn festival cf
          Pomona, when divinations and the consult
          ing of oracles mid omens were universally
          practiced. Lighting bonfires is one of the
          oldest aud most universal of Hallow eve
          usages, yet the Germanic and Celtic na
          tions were both accustomed to kindle them
          on October 31st, centuries before they ever
          heard of the Christian religion, ana its vigil
          of All Hallow eve. It Is probable that the
          boys of those old races indulged, on that
          date, in the same mischievous practices
          which now afford so much pleasure to our
          own youngsters, and no doubt the little
          sons and daughters of the ancient Romans,
          Germans and Celts carminated the munici
          pality (or, in the vulgar, "painted the town
          led") quite as extensively as our own chil
          dren do now by ringing door-bells and run
          ning away before they can be answered,
          beating iv the panels of frontdoors with
          cabbage-heads, misplacing signs, gates and
          fences, aud raising Old Nick generally.
          GKOFFKKY WILI.ISTON CHRISTINE.
          Copyright lbill. AU riyUll reserved.

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1895-11-29/ed-1/?dl=page&amp;q=celebrations+halloween+celebrated&amp;sp=7&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.05,0.931,0.478,0.454,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          'TIS FAIRIES' MGHT.
          ALL Halloween, when to youb
          sight may be, i ween,
          BernUM Tour Fntnrv Spouse's Fsw, la
          All IU Cgllneas and Grace That's 'What
          Think In the "Anld but
          Hardly, I Trow, on This Sldn the Sea.
          A Scotch writer who contributed an
          article to an American newspaper about
          Halloween last year declared himself
          "very much impressed by the almost
          universal observance of Halloween and
          its old customs in America." Ho added
          that the forms most taken by tho observance
          of tho nigh there were, and equally
          to his interest, rather Scotch-Irish
          than English. Farther on ho says that
          "Halloween has always been and still
          trrmcG at lugging or gates.
          is the feast of the year, when gentle
          and simple meet and enjoy themselves
          together, irrespective of social barrier
          and caste, so rigorously observed on
          other occasions.
          This view of Halloween will perhaps
          be entirely new to a majority of those
          who read this writing. Halloween is
          observed in the United States, to be
          sure, and perhaps in some parts of the
          country with some of the same superstition
          that marks its observance among
          tbo&e who dwell on the British isles,
          but this is rarely the fact among those
          of the 'old time American stock. This
          is especially true of those descended
          from the Puritans. Thoso sturdy old
          iconoclasts cast out all sorts of belief
          regarding saints' days and pagan festi
          vals, including even Christmas and the
          Eastertide, in their prohibition of celebrations
          that savored of either the Roman
          church or the Druids. Tho observance
          of Halloween is a mixture of
          both, and I have no doubt that there
          are many thousands in the United
          States, some of whom will read these
          words, who were in as dense ignorance
          of Halloween in their childhood as
          was a business man of one of our
          largest cities with whom I converted
          the other daj.
          "I never heard of Halloween" at all
          when I was a boy, said this man. ""'1
          never heard of Easter either until I
          was 17. of 18. Full knowledge of both
          did not come to me till I 'went away to
          school' with money I had earned work
          ing in the hayneld and the apple orchard,
          and then I read their history in
          the 'Book of Days.' But I knew all
          about Paas (I used to spell it Pees) and
          cabbage night. I used to hide eggs in
          the haymow for days, waiting for the
          first, and the standing cabbages and the
          winging gates of the neighbors used to
          suffer on the second, I tell you.
          Cabbage night! That's the title the
          American boy applies to Halloween.
          And a right lusty, sturdy savage the
          American boy is like to be on that night
          It must be confessed that the joys of
          cabbage night, its breathless exertions
          and runnings here and there in the darkness,
          its pulling of bells and knocking
          at doors, its lifting and lugging of gates,
          its stretching of ropes across paths to
          trip the unwary, all seem rather flat
          and silly to the man whose hair is getting
          gray and who is beginning to be
          fat or rheumatic or perhaps both. But
          they weren't flat and silly some 20 or
          SO years ago, were they, old fellow? Do
          you rememberwhat fun you had stealthily
          tying two cabbages to Deacon Ellis'
          front door knob on cabbage night
          in 186? or 1868? How you then knocked
          at the door and dodged behind the
          big cherry tree in the yard where Tom
          Waters was hidden before you? How
          you then saw the young theological student,
          who was "settin up" with the
          deacon's pretty niece, when he opened
          A LITTLE SERMOX.
          the door? How he was so angry when
          he saw the joke that he began to say
          something that sounded very much like
          a "big, big DV How you snickered so
          loud that he heard you, and darting out
          into the darkness caught you both and
          dragged you into the parlor, where he
          stood you, nearly helpless with mortification,
          before his sweetheart, preached
          you a little sermon, smiling the while,
          which sounded very funny to the young
          lady, but very serious to you? And how
          at the windup he confessed that he had
          himself done such things when he was
          boy, but thought them rude and suggested
          that in future you spend
          een going about restoring unhinged
          gates to their own and t'ie commission
          of other similar good ikeds?
          If that reminiscence be not one of
          yours, then one somewhat similar probably
          is unless yon were a city boy, as I
          was not. I suppose there is no docbt
          that town born lads havo quite as much
          fun in their weak way and manner as
          counrry lads, bet I must confess I have
          never been able to understand how.
          It is not patting it inaccurately, I
          imagine, to say that Halloween, observed
          according to the methods that
          are time honored across the ocean, is a
          new institution, comparatively speaking
          at least, in America. It was brought
          here by settlers who came latter than
          tho Puritans, by immigrants who came
          to better their condition and not for
          liberty of conscience. In some sectiocs
          where the population is largely made
          up of this latter element the old English,
          Scotch and Irish legends undoubtedly
          obtain, yet it is extremely doubtful
          if there is one-tenth of tho Halloween
          superstition anywhere in the
          United States that exists in the mother
          country unless it is among tho negroes
          of tho south, where, since the extreme
          observances of the occasion resemble
          those of the "voodoo doctors" so closely,
          it has been completely assimilated
          into the system of superstitions held by
          the children of Africa.
          A sort of half belief in Halloween
          superstition has been widely disseminated
          by the boarding schools of the
          land, and it is safo to asmno that there
          is far more of Halloween observance
          among the children and young folks of
          the rich and well to do than among
          those whose parents work for wages
          throughout the land. It is quito customary
          nowadays for parents to plan
          Halloween parties for their children, at
          which many of the sports of tho season
          are entered into.
          Bobbing for apples, throwing apple
          peelings over one's shoulder to see what
          initials the peelings will form, pouring
          melted lead into water for a similar
          purpose and the like are favorito diversions
          at these little parties. As diversions
          they are harmless, but in all seriousness
          the inculcation of superstitious at Halloween,
          or any other time, for that matter,
          should be avoided, for the human
          creature is desperately inclined to be
          superstitious, no matter how modern,
          and there is nothing more torturing
          in life than to bo a victim of some belief
          in the significance of omens and
          signs and presentiments, even if the victim
          knows in his inmost heart that
          there is nothing at all to justify such
          belief.
          As a study the folklore of Halloween
          is most interesting. The origin of
          the observance is unmistakably Druid-
          'SisHaB:
          iw.sn S'aUL.
          jn? n isi.
          two nAZL snrrs i threw bto the flame
          ical, and, although the date was shifted
          to that of All Souls' night when Christianity
          usurped heathenism among the
          Teutons, the Anglo-Saxons and the Celts,
          there is nothing about its legends and
          ceremonies that does not savor of the
          pagan. Pulling the kail (or cabbage) to
          find if one's spouse to be will be stout
          or lean is one, and from this no
          doubt came the hilarious phantasies of
          the American cabbage night. Hazel nuts
          and chestnuts play an important part in
          English Halloween observances. The
          poet Gray tells of this most delightfully
          in these lines:
          Two hazl csu I threw Into the flame.
          And tOTOch nut 1 cvb a sweetheart's name.
          ThU with the loudest bounce me Bare amazed.
          That in J flame of brightest color
          As bl&zea nut so marth7p&rtsion grow.
          For 'twas thine own that did so brightly glow.
          In the old days it was believed that
          witches did travel abundantly on Halloween.
          The fairies, too, did then disport
          themselves most friskily, and spells
          then worked that worked no other night.
          The burning bf bonfires was general in
          Wales and Scotland on Halloween, and
          lads and maybe lasses, too, then went
          out masked and dressed in garments of
          quaint design.
          -There were also many games on Halloween
          in other times of which nothing
          is preserved, save in tradition.
          Some of these games were such a3 would
          not be admissible now, for the refine
          ment of those old days was much less
          than that of today, no matter how they
          may have excelled the present in other
          directions. Those games which had for
          their object the discovery of a future
          husband's or wife's identity were naturally
          most popular. Here is a recipe
          for securing an answer to the question
          (apposed to bo most important to every
          girL It is from an ancient publication,
          entitled "The Tree Fortune Teller:"
          "To know whether a woman will
          have the man she wishes get two
          lemon peels. Wear them all day, one in
          each pocket. At night rub the four posts
          of the bedstead with them. If she is to
          succeed, the person will appear in her
          sleep and present her with a couple of
          lemons. If not, there is no hope."
          Here is one from the latitude of Chicago
          It i adapted to city observance,
          but it is not warranted: Fill
          your mouth with salt and run around
          the block, when your true love will of
          a surety show himself.
          Eva Lnvett has put this one into
          rhyme. It is an old favorite with all
          Halloween devotees:
          At midnight lone hempseed is thrown
          (The peeping elrei can see).
          "I sow hempaeed, my love, indeed.
          Cia. garner after mel"

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 6 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-10-29/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=Halloween+soul+souls&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.254,0.004,1.509,1.509,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          On Tuesday
          October 3.1,
          o
          is
          Halloween,
          Halloween.
          Look
          Out
          'lor Your
          ior Yonr
          Future
          Spouse
          THE very mention of Halloween calls
          up visions of ghosts and witches
          and all kinds of uncanny things. It
          ls the one night ln the year when
          J^ even the uninitiated, if they are
          brave enough, may converse with
          spooks and hobgoblins, and may also, if
          they try hard enough, send the immate
          rial part of their being prancing through
          space on all kinds of errands. It Is safe
          to surmise that the latter privilege is not
          often taken advantage fot. It is hard
          enough to keep soul and body together
          without hunting up excuses to separate
          them. But the grand object of all the
          mystic rites peculiar to Halloween is to
          find out who one's future spouse will be
          —that Ing a very Important question
          with those who have never had one.
          The most infallible of the many Infalli
          ble ways by which a girl may get a
          glimpse of her future husband is to re
          tire in silence. That alone is hard
          enough, but that is not all. She must lie
          there, speechless and in the dark, until
          Just before the stroke of 12, when she
          must rise and, standing before the mir
          ror, it an apple while combing her hair.
          If she doesn't see her "future" peeping
          over her shoulder it's because she is des
          tined to be an old maid, or she was too
          scared to look.
          Another way that does not .-equire so
          much courage is to write the alphabet
          on twenty-six little slips of paper, one
          letter on each .-lip, and then urn them
          face down in a basin of water. This done,
          go to bed backward and in silence. Si
          lence seems to be the main requirement
          in ail these endeavors to coax one's af
          finity to make himself, or herself, known.
          Next morning some of the letters in the
          basin will be found face up and the name
          thus revealed will give the desired infor
          mation.
          A more comfortable custom is to wet
          tho sleeve of a shirt and hang it before
          the fire to dry. Then lie in bed and watch
          lt until midnight, when the apparition of
          the future husband or wife will' appear
          and turn the sleeve.
          If a girl has two lovers and cannot de
          cide which one to choose, she may let
          fate settle the matter in the following
          manner. Eat an apple and then, naming
          two Of the seeds, stick one on each cheeK
          and bay:
          Pippin, pippin, I stick thee there.
          j stick thee there.
          That which is true thou mayst declare.
          The one that stays tho longest is the
          must faithful lover, and therefore the
          most desirable.
          There la a custom ln Wales on Hal-
          loween of building a huge bonfire, and
          wher. the fire i--: almost out each member
          of the party gathered about it throws in
          a white stone, marked for future identi
          fication, lv the morning a search is made
          in ti.e embers and if one stone is missing
          It Indicates that the person who threw
          it In will not live to repeat the perform-
          ance the next All Lints' eve.
          Many of the customs mentioned by
          Robert Hums are now- obsolete, but one
          stii: in vogue is that of pulling kail or
          cabbage stalk. A young couple are blind
          folded and then, taking each other by the
          hand, they go into the garden and each
          pulls a stalk at random and they return
          to th.c fireside, where their prizes cause a
          great deal of merriment. As the stalk is
          long or short, straight or crooked, so
          shall the future husband or wife be. The
          quantity of earth sticking to the root in
          dicates the amount of wealth and the
          taste of the pith the kind of temper "tie
          must expect. Finally the stalks are
          placed over the door, and the christian
          names of the next two entering will be
          the names of the future husband and
          wife.
          A custom that is quite common in this
          count! aiso Is to ike three saucers and
          fill c:.. with clean and another with dirty
          water.' The third remains empty. The
          part;. wishing to know his destiny is
          blindfolded and led to tie hearth, where
          the saucers have been arranged. If he
          dips his finger in the clean water he will
          marry a maid, but If in the? dirty water a
          widow will knd him to the altar. The
          empty dish signifies that a life of single
          CARPET TACKS SAVED THE SHIP.
          BUT CAPTAIN JOSHUA SLOCUM HAD A CLOSE CALL.
          Captain Joshua^Slocum. in his solitary
          voyage around tne world in the sloop
          Spray, found a new and exciting use for
          carpet tacks. He thus describes an en
          counter with the Natives of Tierra del
          Fuego:
          Canoes manned by -savages from Fortes
          que now came ln pu-teult. The wind fall
          ing light, they gained on me rapidly till
          coming within hall, when they ceased
          paddling, and a bow-*ggcd savage stood
          up and called to me, V Yammerschooner I
          yammerschooner!" whati ls their begging
          term. I said "No!" M»w. I was not for
          letting them know that I was alone, and
          6o I stepped Into the ctpln, and. passing
          through the hold, came -put at the fore
          scuttle, changing my Blkhes as I went
          along. That made two kien. Then the
          piece of bowsprit whioh >had sawed -oit
          blessedness is in store for him.
          Apples and nuts play a very important
          part in the mystic rites of Halloween. One
          way to find out If one's sweetheart is
          true Is to place three nuts upon .lie bar
          of the grate or on the hearth, naming the
          nuts for the loved one. If a nut cracks
          or jumps, look for another sweetheart
          right away, for the one you have will
          surely be unfaithful. If a nut burns that
          Is a sign that your affection ls reciprocated.
          but if two of the ruts burn together the
          young lady making the trial may as well
          begin preparing her trousseau at once,
          for there will surely be an early wed-
          ding.
          Halloween parties must always be made
          as weird and uncanny as possible, and
          any one with original id< ie may give
          them full scope on these occasions. One
          very quaint affair that 1 recall may
          serve as a model.
          In the first place the Invitations were
          most unique* Witches and goblins ran riot
          over the card and the utmost secrecy in
          regard to the approaching event was ex-
          acted. Silence, too, was enjoined,, and
          every one was veiled, and it certainly was
          a very ghostly crowd that gathered
          promptly at the appointed time in the
          dimly lighted hallway. Suddenly the
          sound of a bell -was heard, soft and- muf-
          fled, as If it were high up In an old church
          tower, and as it struck 9 the doors were
          thrown open and the young people were
          ushered into a veritable witches' den.
          Death heads, made from pumpkins, with
          a small lighted candle inside, grinned
          from the mantel, the cornices and the
          most unexpected places. Huge cobwebs,
          In which were monster spiders, were
          stretched across the corners and over the
          mirrors. Immense bats with outspread
          wings were apparently flying through the
          air and great owls glared from every pos
          sible resting place. In the fireplace, the
          grate had been removed and in its stead
          a large caldron was simmering over a pale
          green blaze.
          The hostess and her assistants were
          witches, gowned in flowing black robes
          and crownev with tall, pointed caps. In-
          visible music of a weird character added
          to the uncanniness of the scene. The
          gentlemen were all in an adjacent room
          and tbe hostess, taking a lady by the
          hand, would advance with tier and knock
          three times on the door with the small
          broom she carried. In answer to her
          knock a gentleman would appear, and
          Offering the lady his arm retire to a dis
          tant part of the room. When, in this
          manner, the couples had all been paired
          off the wltchefe wave,] their arms and
          crooned in the most approved witch
          manner and the screeching of the violins
          outside became truly blood-curdling. Sud
          denly, with a crash and a bang, the noise
          ceased and the room was filled with light
          When the light revealed the partners that
          at Buenos Ayres, and which I had still
          on board. I arranged forward on the look-
          out, dressed as a seaman, attaching a line
          by which I could pull It into motion.
          That made three of us. and we did not
          want to "yammerschooner;" but for all
          that the savages came on faster than be-
          fore. I saw that besides four at the pad-
          dles In the canoe nearest to me. there
          were others in the bottom, and that they
          were shifting hands often. At eighty
          yards I fired a shot across the bow of the
          nearest' canoe, at which they all stopped,
          but only for a moment. Seeing that they
          persisted ln coming nearer, I fired the
          second shot so close to the chap who
          wanted to "}*ammerschooner" that he
          changed hie mind quickly enough and bel-
          lowed with fear. "Bueno yo via Isla,"
          and sitting down in his canoe, he rubbed
          his starboard cat-bead for some time. I
          HERE ARE SOME ANCIENT CUSTOMS
          THAT YOU WILL FIND MOST INTER-
          ESTING TO EXPERIMENT WITH
          fate had given each for the evening there
          as a good deal of merriment. At a sig-
          nal from the First Witch a couple went
          Into the outer darkness to pull "kail"
          stalks. Of course they had been prepared
          beforehand and there was not a straight
          one in the whole lot. After this ordeal
          had been gone through by every one a
          decrepit old hag. with a real, live owl
          perched on her shoulder, entered the
          room. On her arm hung a basket full
          of nuts. Passing through the crowd she
          gave each a nut and then.' standing by
          the fireplace, she mumbled some unin-
          telllgible Jargon and the room suddenly
          became darkened again. Stooping over
          the caldron she muttered an Incantation
          and red fire Immediately blazed from Its
          depths. She then tottered out of the
          room, which again was illuminated as she
          disappeared. The nuts, when cracked,
          were found to contain a fortune, written,
          on a slip of paper. For example, "You
          will have many trials until the age of 30,
          when good luck will come to you." The
          nuts for the gentlemen were tied with
          red ribbons and those for the ladies with
          blue. .V
          During the evening all sorts of games,
          peculiar to Halloween, were added to the
          programme. A stick was suspended hori-
          zontally from the celling and on one end
          was a short piece of lighted candle, while
          an apple was stuck *on the other, and
          the whole thing set whirling. A small
          basket was then passed around in which
          were a number of slips of paper. The
          unfortunate who drew the paper with a
          skull and cross-bones on It had to furnish
          was thinking of a good port captain's ad
          vice when I pulled the trigger, and I
          must have aimed pretty straight; how
          ever, a miss was as good as a mile for
          Mr. "Black Pedro," as he it was, and no
          other, a leader In several bloody massa
          cres. He now directed the course of his
          canoe for the island and the others fol
          lowed him. I knew by his Spanish lingo
          and by his full heard that he was the
          villain I have named a renegade mongrel,
          and the worst murderer in Tierra del
          Fuego. The authorities had been In
          search of' him for two years. The Fue
          gans are not bearded. At
          night, March 8, at anchor in the snug
          cove at .the. Turn, every heart-beat
          counted thanks. Hers I pondered on the
          events of the last few days, and, strangely
          enough, Instead of feeling rested from
          sitting or lying down, I now began to
          THE SUNDAY OALIi.
          amusement for the rest by trying to get
          a bite from the apple on the whirling
          stick. Luckily for the girls, a man drew
          the fatal slip, but before he had burned
          his mustache off the First Witch took
          pity on him and clapped her hands. Over
          the door leading Into the dining-room a
          dark, heavy portiere hung and at the slg
          nal an apple rolled under the curtain and
          went spinning over the floor. "It was fol
          lowed by another and then ether, until
          everybody had one. Knives were then
          passed around and a merry half-hour was
          spent In peeling the apples and throwing
          the unbroken skin over the shoulder In
          such a manner as to form the Initial of
          the future husband or wife, In one of
          the apples a needle was Imbedded in the
          core, indicating that the finder would
          enjoy a domestic or wedded life. Another
          contained a pen. foretelling a literary
          career, and in still another a tiny pencil
          was buried, signifying a life devoted to
          art. In a fourth a small piece of wood
          was hidden on which the word "music"
          had been written.
          A few moments before midnight the
          merry-makers were all taken out the
          kitchen door and separated Into two
          groups, the girls on one side and the
          gentlemen on the other. At the first
          stroke of twelve both groups started and
          ran, one going one way and the other in
          the opposite direction, all to meet at the
          front door. The first couple to reach the
          goal would be the first to marry— not each
          other, necessarily— and the last to arrive
          were doomed to a lonely existence
          When the race was over, the breathless
          feel .laded and worn; but a hot meal of
          venison stew soon put me right, so that
          I could sleep. As drowsiness came on I
          first sprinkled the deck with the tacks
          that my old friend Sambllch had given
          me, and then I turned in.
          Now, it Is well known that one cannot
          istep on a tack without saying something
          about it. A pretty good Christian will
          whistle when he steps on the "commercial
          end" of a carpet tack; a savage will howl
          and claw the alr, and that was just what
          happened that night about 12 o'clock
          while I- was asleep in the cabin, where
          the savages thought they "had me,"
          sloop and all. They changed their minds,
          however, when they stepped on deck, for
          then they thought that I or somebody
          else had them. I had no need of a dog;
          they howled like a pack of hounds. I
          had hardly uso for a gun. They jumped
          pell-mell, some into their canoes and
          some. Into the sea, to cool off, I suppose,
          and there was a deal of free language
          over It as they went. I fired the rascals
          a salute of several guns t when I came on
          deck, to -let them know that I was at
          home, and then I turned in again, feeling
          sure that- 1 should not be disturbed any
          more by people who left In bo great a
          hurry.
          laughing crowd was summoned to supper,
          and there another surprise awaited them.
          The decorations in the dining-room were
          red. even the tablecloth being of the same
          brilliant hue.' Over the center of the
          round table a huge owl. with outspread
          wings, was suspended from the ceiling.
          In its claws it held the ends of four long
          red ribbons, the other ends of which were
          held in the corners of the room, near the
          celling, by bats, lizards and spiders. The
          shade on the lamp was red crepe paper,
          THE BOERS AS THEY REALLY ARE,
          By MISS SANNIE KRUGER, NIECE OF OOM PAUL KRUGER.
          Continued from Page Twenty-one.
          the wedding customs. The suitor takes
          the girl of his choice to some lachergoot
          (confectionery). If she refuses the gift
          that ends the courtship. If not he sits in
          the midst of the coffee-drinking family
          for an hour or more. Finally' he Is left
          alone with the girl of his choice. T But the
          wise tant according to custom puts a
          limit on the length of his visit.- She marks
          the wax candle with a needle, meaning
          that i the visit must only last until the
          candle burns to the mark.
          I s could tell you of many more quaint
          customs, but It was not for: that- I under
          took this task. Rather _to convince you
          that i a Boer girl ls not a semi-savage.
          on which had been applied owls and bats
          of some black material. The punch was
          red, so was the frosting on the cake—
          which, by the way, was crescent-shaped
          and surmounted by a tiny doll, dressed all
          in red. as a witch. The souvenirs were
          also small witch-dolls for the ladies and
          owls for the men, both of which, on In
          vestigation, proved to be bonbon boxes.
          In Ireland, the observance of Hallow
          een assumes. In many respects, a religious
          character. It is a custom In many dis
          My English always surprises people Into
          comment. True, I speak with less accent
          than most Boer girls, having a natural
          aptitude for languages and having trav
          eled so much.
          But the rising generation of Boers are
          ail well educated. Both English and
          Dutch are taught In the schools. Oom
          Paul understands English as well as I do
          myself. Many times when 'playing or
          dancing for him I would forget and make
          some remark in English. He would al
          ways chide -me for it, saying. "I could
          speak English as well as a rooinek (red
          neck— Dutch for Englishman), but I never
          forget I am a Boer."
          Like all Boer girls I am an excellent
          ■hot and I fervently wish that I were
          trlcts to bake what are called "soul
          cakes" on that day, which are given to the
          poor, who go from door to door begging.
          The gift of a cake is always accompanied
          with a request to pray for the souls of the
          dead. The recipient of these "soul cakes"
          is generally very profuse In his promises
          to pray dnd calls down the blessings of
          heaven on everything he or she can think
          of. Another custom is to burn a lighted
          candle in every wind in the house,
          which gives a very picturesque effect
          along the country roads.
          There ls a custom among the poorer
          classes In England, also, or begging on
          Halloween, for what Is known there as
          "dole bread." In several districts a fan-
          tastic arrangement, called "Old Hob," ls
          carried about from house to house, ac
          companied by a crowd of young people,
          singing doggerel begging rhymes. Old
          Hob consists of a skeleton of a horse's
          head, mounted on a broomstick, and with
          a sheet wrapped about and concealing the
          person who ls carrying It-
          Shaw, in his history of the Province of
          Moray, considers the festivities of Hal-
          loween as a sort of harvest-home rejoic-
          ing— a thanksgiving for the safe ingather
          ing of the produce of the fields. What
          ever may have been the original motive
          for this "gathering together of the clans"
          on the eve of All Saints, the young people
          who make merry nowadays have only one
          object In view— to discover, lf possible,
          their affinity, to find that mysterious he
          or she for whom we are all of us con
          tinually seeking. Sometimes these "affin
          ities" are a little careless and don't pair
          off just right, so the boys and girls who
          try their fate on this next Halloween
          must not neglect the warnings and
          prophecies which that night of mystery
          will surely bring.

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 7 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052116/1905-10-26/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=HALLOWEEN+Halloween+Hallow+Hallowmas&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.461,0.534,0.249,0.236,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          HALLOWEEN
          is 4
          XXSXXW K sssssssssssSssssssss
          Polythofstn having many phases
          hnd also many festivals Among the
          Celts who Inhabited ancient Brkain
          two of tho host Important of these
          fell In the early parts of May and of
          November and were called Ualtnno
          or Dcltoln festivals a name signify
          ing Sun god and the riles with
          which they wore celebrated really
          possessed many of tho characteris
          tics of the fetes of those very Interest
          Ing people Ihe Fire Worshipers At
          the beginning of a Boltoln colebra
          tlon all tho fires of the community
          were extinguished not so much M
          ono live coal must bo left I among the
          ashes of the chlmney4hon with
          ceremony or Bong and sacrifice the
          priests kindled the necdflro by the
          friction of n rope drawn rapidly
          about a post From the sacred spark
          thus obtalnediian altar flro was built
          from which all tile fires In the coun
          tryside were relighted This need
          lire was believed tp have the pow
          to scans away witches dsvlls fairies
          and the dcmonsvof dlucitx hat lurk
          ed about human habitations within
          the magic Circle qf Us Vght no evil
          spirit might work Its fatal spell
          There Is nothing1 lo ivftlcn people
          cling with more per hMiicy than lo
          their supcritltlonn aftd tlvi t praitlrcs
          that pertain thereto arci so t wait
          that when tho early Christians began
          to propagate their religion in leah
          en lands they wisely mnd nu light
          on tho fete days of the pcopUs tiny
          wished to convert inwrougfit rs
          they wero with fanatical Miperstl
          tlon rather did they lack lo Chris
          tlanlze these days by associating
          them with some of their own f cull
          vats gradually letting alto snctcd
          rights supersede tie ici stn rues
          Thus tho heathen YuHtdfc became
          the holy season of Chijlbtinas tho
          springtime Qelteln was nib de to corn
          clde with Easter and the autumnal
          one fortunately falling on Nov 1
          was transformed Into one of the most
          beautiful festivals of the religion of
          Calvary Hallowmas or AllSaints
          day But though the day thus lost
          Its heathen slgnlflcancer nany of Us
          heathen beliefs clung tdtll l uud the
          echo of these weakenddby clvlllza
          lion have come down thefiges tons
          Halloween was the eve ot Hallow
          mas and on that night ghosts gob
          llns witches and Alrles were belteV
          edto be turned leos 1 uPon tho Perth
          tit a ifs ati3itl na v tl l that hid
          tho futtife Jung so waveringly that
          one by proper signs allli devlcjs
          might get a peep bohlnd lt Thus It
          came to be the favorite night tor
          tho testing fortune
          In Scotland where the 1e1l01n 1
          perstltlohs smoldered tong girls
          wound tholr clews of yarmbut of win
          tows expecting to find their future
          husbands holding the ends and both
          lads and lassies stole out In tho darK
          to BOW the hemp seed that a future
          spouse would como behind nnd hal
          row For song unexplained reaso
          haps sonic faint faint thread of
          heredity running backward through
          tho ramifications of tlmo and nations
          to tho story of tho garden of Eden l
          the njiple has always boon considered
          a fateful fruit big with prophecy of
          things to come In many tests of
          fortune does It play a part Eat one
          before a mirror inn darkened room
          on Halloween and your future I
          spouso will look over your shoulder
          Throw tho pool over your left shoul
          der mill It will form the Initial of tho
          one you ore to Quarry Cut It open
          and take from It two I seeds stick
          theso on either eyelid Vnd watcll to
          sco which will stick the longer for
          that ono Is to win In loves race A
          mischievous girl will bear close
          watching III this test or slit may
          help on the CRUSOOt her favorite
          s ultor by winking oft his rival Then
          them Is tho timehonored way of
          counting tho apple seed One I
          love two I love three i 1 love l I say
          four I lovo with all my heart and
          jflyo1 cast away If l thoro arc five
          fired a girl may soften the prophecy
          Ip her sweetheart by the lines of the
          x
          song
          UBut counting secds Is not i t tho way
          A bodys love to ProvoM
          For tho very ono I caso away
          Is Just the ono Move I
          Nuts also become4 fortunetollers
          on tho mystic night of Hollowoon
          the prettiest test being that of burn
          Ing them on a hot shoveUnftor nam
          lag them tho quickly burning ones
          arc tho changeable lovers thin slow
          ly I burning ones are the mon who will
          bo constant and true The whlto off
          a hardboiled eggAllcd with salt
          and oaten on retiring alsobocomes
          a rovonlor of destiny for In dreams
          tho future spouse will bring n cup of
          water tto the thirsty sleeper For
          Halloween parties the Fortune Hags
          and the Candle Trials are very pretty I
          For the first two baga nre prepared
          filled with answers to the questions
          When will I bo married 1 The
          more ludicrous the n answers which
          are to be read aloud the mow fun
          they will evoke Fon thf candle
          tesr use II ho colored tailors for I
          Christmas trees Two nets must he
          jirbvldcil one for tho girls and one
          Ifor Ut boys Each cnuclle is nun
          bored by n small card tied to It
          Front other fortune baS8ono for
          boys and one for glrll1lhe guests
          draw larger cards which are mini
          bored on one side and on tho other
          bear a fortune verso Each I guest
          matches the number of this card
          with the card on the candles Thci
          the lapers arc all lighted at n bIg
          necdflre Candle provided for the
          purpose and tho guests gathcrltij
          In a circle read their destinies by
          the light of the colored tapers For
          Instance No 1 may bo a green can
          Alt and the holder may read
          Your sweet heart will Jilt you Just at
          suro
          As this green candle burns down
          And youll waste your wealth and
          live and dio L
          The crustiest bach In tho town
          Or a girl may hold this one
          Hercfe a1 fortune taper green
          Uy its twinkling light Is seen
          Many things to come to you
          Bags with mortoy bursting through
          Beaux aplenty to your string
          And a goldcn wedding ring
          Pink calldleq
          If pink Is tho candle youvo chosen
          tonight
          Theres n marriage for money and
          riches In sight
          Red candle
          This Is the red candles prophecy
          Youll boss him whosoeer ho be
          When you put on your bridal wreath
          Youll rake tho bit between your
          0
          teeth
          White candle
          Many good i things for your future
          life
          This moonwhite taper shows
          A bank account and a coach and four
          And a wife with aturncdup nose
          Or
          You hold tonight a candle white
          And by the radlanco shed
          A lover true will come to you
          Ere many moons arc sped
          These verses may be legion After
          these have been read aloud a for
          tuneteller dressed ns a Salem witch
          will keep tho company in excellent
          spirits for a time A fitting close to
          a Halloween evening is the telling
          of ghost stories by the company In
          turn the lights being tho first extln
          guished and saucers of salt anti
          ted with alcohol placed on the floor
          In tho middle of the clrclo the
          weird flickering of Ythose ghost
          lights glvosan uncanny aspect to the
          faces and figures of the company
          Another way to bass the evening sa
          ghost dance to which tho guests
          all como Shrouded In sheets and
          masked In white In imltatldn of tho
          spirits supposed to bo abroad on
          Halloween

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 8 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-03/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=Hallowe%27en+celebrated+celebration</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          OUR SPECIAL FEATURE PAGE
          nO holiday on the calendar deyeu^.
          more for Its charm upon tradtlon and
          the customs handed down from genera
          tion to generation- than does that fateful
          night of mirth and mystery Hallowe'en.
          Most of oar American holidays com
          memorate historic events within the past
          entnxy and half and consequently can
          not of course, have any of the charac
          teristics of ancient ceremonial. Even
          Christmas has, in Its observance, been
          modernised ont of all semblance of the
          old-tfme celebration. Hallowe'en, how
          •r, not only retains Its time-honored
          significance and long-established ritual
          trot finds Its chief attraction In these re
          minders of bygone periods.
          The festival of the night of October 81
          has a number of different designations,
          though none are so commonly nsed as
          Hallowe'en. The others are All Hallow
          ¦yen, Nutcrack Night and Snapapple
          Night, the latter two being derived of
          course from practices associated with
          the occasion. Hallowe'en derives Its
          most common name as the eve or vigil
          of All Saints' or All Hallows Day (No
          vember 1). From time out of mind this
          has been heralded as a night when
          witches, devils and other mlschlef-mak-
          Ing beings go abroad on their baneful
          midnight errands. By a strange coinci
          dence, however, this same night Is sap
          posed to be devoted by the fairies to a
          grand anniversary celebration.
          The traditions of Hallowe'en also teach
          that on no 4ther night In the twelve
          month do sach supernatural Influences
          prevail as after dark on the final day of
          October. According to ancient beliefs the
          spirits of the dead then wander about and
          In some Instances the spirits of living per
          sons have conferred upon them the tem
          porary power to Join the ghostly clan.
          Persons who have nad the good fortune
          to be born on October 31 are especially
          likely to be warned or advised by the
          elves on each recurring anniversary of
          A LITERARY PILGRIMAGE
          3CST as thousands of tourists visit Ob
          erammergau to witness the Passion Play
          and hasten to Bayreuth for Wagnerlan
          festivals «o enrh year nearly the same
          number visit Weimar, the Athens of mod
          ern Europe. Ever since the two great
          est German poets made this place sacred
          with their memories, scholars and writers
          no less than musicians have found it a
          worthy retreat. Dickens and Thacksrey
          spent some time here and George Eilot
          and Madame de Stael Bought Weimar as
          a place of Inspiration. Amalla Winter
          in her charming Weimar album describes
          the many brilliant English and Rus
          sians who came to take tea with Goethe's
          daughter-in-law, and spent the evening
          listening to the reading of German and
          English poetry. An Englishman of that
          day wrote In his diary these words In
          memory of Goethe and the days he made
          golden: "Sad heart why do you awaken
          In me memories of those golden days
          that flew bye so quickly. In the classic
          town on the llm noted for its culture,
          life In the open air and pleasure. Weimar,
          oh, yonr name and Its associations haunt
          me now." There are still plenty of ncso
          elation to delight the thousands of trav
          elers who spend several happy days
          ¦midst these literary haunts.
          Weimar ts an attractive place In Itself,
          Hallowe'en
          A HOLIDAY OF
          TRADITIONS
          their natal day, but sometimes, so It Is
          said, other persons have the gift of con
          versing with the airy visitants on such
          occasions.
          Saint Matrimony is the patron saint
          of Hallowe'en and Indeed this autumn
          holiday Is best known as the night of all
          nights for peering Into the future and
          especially for discovering just what sort
          of husband or wife fate has selected for
          each unmarried participant In the rites.
          It Is this function of the holiday which
          helps to keep Its observance alive with
          the young people of the nation and not a
          few of their elders who are yet youthful
          In spirit. Not only are the mysterious
          spirits that are abroad on Hallowe'en
          supposed to be Infallible In their verdicts
          but it Is also of manifest advantage that
          they demand neither fee nor reward for
          piercing the veil that hides the future.
          The performance of some very simple
          ceremony Is all that Is exacted of the
          curious young man or woman who would
          learn Interesting particulars regarding the
          destined life-partner.
          The origin of Hallowe'en seems to be
          hidden In 'an Intermingling of classic
          mythology and Christian superstitions.
          The plan of making nnts and apples con
          spicuous in the Hallowe'en festivities Is
          traced back to the custom of the ancient
          Romans to hold on November 1 a feast
          to Pomona, the goddess of fruits and
          seeds, at which time there was a formal
          opening of the stores of eatables laid
          up In summer for use during the winter.
          On this same date occurred the great
          autumn festival to the sun with which the
          Druids or ancient Celts celebrated thanks
          giving for their harvest and It was the
          belief of the Druids that 'on the eve of
          their holiday the present Hallowe'en
          it rests In a valley surrounded by moun
          tains and splendid woods of the Tliur
          ingen forests. The air Is refreshed by n
          small river which wanders geutly and
          romantically about the meadows, ami
          woods and again rus'aes on so forcibly
          It must be held back by a dam. The
          town Is adorned with a beautiful park
          and some splendid monuments and some
          very attractive homes. The Hotel Erb
          prinas Is one of the show places because
          of Its historic associations. This hotel
          was formerly a large inn and was for
          ninny months at a time tha home cf Ger
          many's greatest poets, musicians and
          painters. When Franz Llsst first came
          to Weimar this was his only home for
          five months. Here he practised and
          played for many of bis friends and wrote
          many of the compositions whlqji were
          later brought out at the Opera house.
          His bedroom and the room occupied by
          Goethe are the two most popular rooms
          In the House and guests bid high to say
          they lived In tha Lint and Goethe rooms.
          There Is nothing especially noteworthy
          In Its furnishing except the beautiful
          writing desk at which the great musi
          cian and composer wrote. The top Is
          shaped like a Greek; temple decorated
          with mirrors and marquetry wood. The
          rest of tha furniture Is limited to a
          wooden bed, a small table, waahstand,
          •JLOS ANGELES HERALD SUNDAY SUPPLEMENT
          the Lord of Death summoned those
          wicked souls that had within the year
          been condemned to henceforth occupy the
          bodies of animals.
          The people of England have long set
          store by an elaborate observance of Hal
          lowe'en, but even antedating their al
          legiance was that of the Irish. In the
          Emerald Isle It was the custom from
          the earliest days for each household to
          set out on this holiday the best viands
          It could afford, apples and nuts being in
          evitable features of the menu. In not a
          few Instances peasants went from house
          to house collecting breadcake, bntter,
          cheese, eggs and other eatables suitable
          for a feast. Indeed, throughout Great
          Britain bread or cake has long been asso
          ciated with the Hallowe'en feast, and
          even today In many English households a
          cake Is baked for each member of the
          family. An early Hallowe'en observance
          was that of ringing the church bells all
          night long, but a stop was put to this by
          King Henry VIII.
          As hasNbeen said, many of the features
          of the Hallowe'en program In auclent
          times have been continued to this day
          but for the most part tho customs which
          were once ceremonies of belief now
          observed only In jest. Hallowe'en being
          the first of the autumn and winter holi
          days and, for the young people, the first
          break In the school year Is Invariably wel
          comed with especial enthusiasm. The
          circumstance that Hallowe'en Is not a
          national holiday does not In the least
          a large round table and an oblong table
          with gilt trimmings.
          But the furnishing of the roo:.i Is very
          flue to that which the Schiller room
          knew. The small dimensions, the single
          bed, the plain writing desk snd the one
          chair tell better than words the struggle
          and hardships which followed this great
          and talented poet all his days. Very dif
          ferent from the comfortable quarters
          Goethe enjoyed. Goethe's room was far
          more spacious and better furnished. His
          room had two large windows with a bal
          cony commanding a splendid view of the
          old Castle walls with their strange carv
          ings, a small house opposite with a
          strange snn-dlal and the large market
          square. Goethe's bed '.s especially In
          teresting because It Is built In the wall
          and has linen curtains bung before It.
          Tht most elaborate piece of furniture Is
          the writing desk, an exact duplicate of
          the one Liszt used. It Is the U..-t on
          affect Its observance since Its festivities
          are for the most part reserved for the
          period after nightfall when the work-a
          day world is presumably at leisure.
          Various schemes for obtaining matri
          monial forecasts on Hallowe'en have been
          handed down to the present generation.
          The roasting of nuts is an essential pre
          lude to most of them. Some Inquisitive
          maidens nre wont to place a number of
          nuts, each bearing the name of a lover,
          on the bars of h grate or among the em
          bers. According to the ritual If a nut
          crneks or jumps the lover will prove un
          faithful whereas if It begins to blaze or
          burn he hss regard for the person making
          the test. If a nut burns quietly and
          brightly especial sincerity of affection
          Is supposedly Indicated. Similarly If nuts
          named for a girl and her lover burn In
          unTson an early wedding Is to be ex
          pected.
          Apples vie with nuts as Hallowe'en vehi
          cles for discovering the Intentions of
          Cupid. Indeed one of the best known
          ruses, and perhaps the one most generally
          which he Is supposed to hnvi written
          many of his most ardent lqve-letters and
          pints of his Faust. Though many noted
          guests have dined and spent some hours
          in this lan, two other names have made
          the place historic. Napoleon lived here
          some weeks when he once paid a visit
          to Weimar. In the rooms is a large em
          pire table on which he Is suprised to
          have written many Important state let
          ter*. The great painter Mentzel also
          lived here a long time and painted some
          of his greatest masterpieces.
          There Is the same terrace overlooking
          tht garden where Goethe gar* a dinner
          to Prince Augustus; Lieut and others. It
          Is here whispered that he often paid for
          Schiller's supper when his friend was
          short of money. Liszt also gave sorao
          famous dinners here, played for his
          Ruests and discussed his compositions at
          mgth. A stone's throw from tha hotel
          Is the royal park, a beautiful wooded
          practiced at the general time Is that In
          which the credulous maiden eats an apple
          before a looking glass while combing her
          hair, confident that If directions be fol
          lowed explicitly the face of her destined
          conjugal partner will be seen In the mir
          ror as though peeping over her shoulder.
          Equally well known Is the scheme wliere-
          I'v any maiden may find out the first
          letter of the name of her future hus
          band by peeling an apple, taking the
          paring by one end and after swinging
          It three times around her head allowing
          It to fall In whatever fashion It may.
          It must be confessed that some slight
          stretch of Imagination may be necessary
          to construe the position of the paring as
          indicating a desired letter.
          There has been transplanted to. the United
          States from Scotland another means of
          peeping into the matrimonial lottery. By
          this plan the young women go hand In
          haud, bliudfolded, or at least with eyes
          closed, to the cabbage patch and each
          pulls the first plant met with. Earth on
          place cut by the Urn murmuring with
          waterfalls and spanned with rustic
          bridges. In the summer-time the park
          is crowded with mothers giving their
          children an airing and men resting and
          enjoying the beauty of the surrounding
          after their day of hard toll. They may
          well rest here for a more beautiful park
          is difficult to Imagine. Here is seen a
          wonderful canopy of greeu made by the
          over-arching of beautiful trees. Behind
          the trees la seen the frame of the rushing
          waters made gladder by the laughter and
          prattle of happy children. Blending with,
          this modern note are interesting views.
          Going down a steep hill one comes upon
          Shakespere's monument. Anything more
          beautiful can not be imagined. The poet
          Is represented as a young man resting
          on a rock and looking out on the world
          with a happy air of contentment At his
          feet are strewn manuscripts, a Jester's
          doll and a wreath of roses. His exprea
          the root of the cabbage thus selected
          signifies dowry. The shape and size of
          the vegetable denote the appearance and
          size of the future spouse and the taste
          of the heart and stem Indicate his dis
          position. Nor Is all the Hallowe'en prog
          nosticating for the benefit of the fair
          sex. There have been designed for ardent
          swains numerous forms of divination, the
          best known of which Is that whereby the
          smitten youth descends cellar stairs
          with a randle In one hand and a mirror
          in the other, hoping to have the face of a
          sweetheart reflected back to him from
          the glass.
          All the Hallowe'en pranks above men
          tioned and a host of others are intro
          duced as adjuncts of the Hallowe'en par
          ties which now constitutes one of tho
          most popular forms of entertaining in
          this country. That tradition has decreed
          the occasion one of mystery as well as a
          night of jollity and laughter paves the
          way for unique entertainments and many
          quaint conceits In the line of amusements
          have been devised by resourceful hosts
          slon Is co alive he looks as though he
          were ready to play Orlando or Benedict.
          To become acquainted with the people
          of the town one should visit Weimar
          during the week of Schutzenfest. a hunt
          ers festival which lasts eight days. In
          this week of gayety is much drinking,
          merrymaking and target shooting.
          Though target shooting is now consid
          ered as a sport, these sturdy Saxons
          show by their strength and skill that
          they have not forgotten the early method
          of warfare In which their forefathers ex
          celled.
          But there Is so much to see in Weimar
          one can not afford to let ones imagina
          tion ran riot with fancies. A good start-
          Ing point Is the Schiller house. Schiller
          lived on the second floor and the apart
          ment Is very homely. 'It consists of a
          living-room, workroom, dining-room and
          bedchamber. The living-room is the
          most elaborately furnished. It has cup
          boards which served for the keeping of
          books and dishes. In one corner of the
          room Is a spinet and a guitar. In a
          cabinet on the other side are seen dishes,
          rings, letters, snuff-boxes and walking
          sticks, used- by the poet. The single
          wooden bedstead in which Schiller
          brenthed his last 1b placed In the work
          room. It is piled high with ribbons
          which adorned wreaths sent by all na
          tions when he died. As one gazes on
          these faded ribbons ones eyes fill with
          tears and the lips whisper- "They came
          too late. Why did not me world help
          and appreciate this wonderful genius
          when his soul needed their sympathy and
          protection." Not far from the Schiller
          house is the library of which Goethe was
          director for many years. The building
          showed that he was almost as good an
          architect as poet. Not satisfied with the
          appearance 'of the place he remodeled the
          hall so that the pictures, busts and books
          would be in good light without being hid
          den one by the other. There are busts
          of many of the men who made Weimar
          known to the world. In this number are
          seen Goethe, Schiller, Herder, Wetland,
          Karl August, Lavater, Napoleon and
          Madame de Stael. To one side is a large
          room overlooking the garden where
          Goethe worked many years and is sup
          posed to have plnuued and written the
          greatest part of bis Faust.
          Mora interesting still Is the Goethe
          summer-bouse, a simple frame dwelling
          surrounded by a lovely garden and wood.
          i
          and hostesses. Hallowe'en has become
          especially popular at schools and colleges,
          as a brief season given over to the pranks
          of the students. Particularly Is there a
          fantastic observance of the holiday at
          girls' boarding schools and women's col
          leges.
          Novelty Is the keynote of everything
          connected with a Hallowe'en festivity.
          Like as not the Invitations, menu cards,
          tally cards, etc. are bespattered with
          representations of witches riding brooms,
          blinking owls, broad-winged bats and
          pumpkins while for decorative purposes
          there are pressed Into service a variety
          of nature's vivid- hued products such as
          cornstalks, pumpkins, carrots, russet oak
          leaves and green plno boughs. Finally
          the, refreshments, which are an lndlspen
          sable feature, Include apples, nuts, grapes
          and other autumn delicacies.
          Since mystic rites are to be essayed and
          ghost stories and other spooky subjects
          are likely to be among the topics of con
          versation, It Is not only permissible but
          appropriate that there should be no bril
          liant Illumination of the scene of a Hal
          lowe'en party and this enables the use of
          candles set In hollowed carrots or the em
          ployment of Jack-o-lanterns.
          Certain well-known American host
          esses, famous as the originators of oddi
          ties, have given Hallowe'en entertain
          ments in barns and attics and In one In
          stance a cellar was utilised, black drap
          eries and the symbol of the skull and
          cross-bones adding to the "creepy" at
          mosphere. Highly popular as Hallowe'en
          entertainments are, masquerade parties
          of one kind or another and shadow pan
          tomimes have come Into extensive vogue
          In recent years. Some of the games which
          are now regarded as indispensable to a
          Hallowe'en frolic have no significance as
          matrimonial barometers. Foremost among
          these Is the prank of ducking for apples.
          The apples are set afloat In a tub and
          each person essays to catch one of the
          floating prises with the teeth, bis hands
          being tied behind him. The popping of
          corn at an open fire, fortune telling and
          other old-fashioned diversions are also re
          vived for the benefit of the younger gen
          eration on Hallowe'en.

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 9 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-10-24/ed-1/?sp=38&amp;q=Hallowe%27en+HALLOWE%27EN+celebrations+celebration&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.258,-0.127,1.517,1.517,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          NOW approaches the witch's!
          hour, when, hand in band with'
          .ia<*k-o'-lantern, she is prepared to
          scamper across the curtain for
          an interlude of frolic.
          The black cat is with us
          again, and the bat, and the owl. The
          cauldron bubbles, the chestnuts barn
          upon the hearth, the Hallowe'en cake
          gives up its ghostly prophecy of wealth,
          matrimony or a life of single blessedness, i
          In a thousand boarding schools a thou-
          sand girls will creep down the cellar|
          stairs holding a mirror and a candle as
          the hour strikes twelve, looking fearfully,
          for the reflected face which is to tell'
          them of the future, and in more than a
          thousand apartment houses—where there
          are no cellar stairs—young women will|
          eat an apple before a mirror and hold a I
          candle by whose light they expect to see
          that same prophetic vision.
          If it weren't for jack o' lantern the
          celebration of Hallowe'en might be;
          rather a gloomy affair, for looking into|
          the future in darkened rooms and watch-1
          ing one's fellow chestnut hop away from!
          one on the hearth are not always cheer
          ing diversions; but jack-o'-lantern, the
          Uing of the night, is the jolliest of pre
          siding geniuses, and, besides, there is
          the Hallowe'en feast, a most temptine j
          repast, to keep one's spirits from flag
          ging in the midst of the general unloos
          ing of the black arts.
          HALLOWE'EN 'nativities are always
          very popular with girls, and they are
          possible for every one, for the cele-,
          '.ration of the night has one great advan-j
          tage in the fact that its m}'stic rites and]
          ceremonies can be jusC as well and hap
          pily performed by three or four persons as
          by a large number. Naturally the sort of
          Hallowe'en entertainment which Is ar-,
          ranged for a small gathering is not satis
          factory for a large one. It has usually
          been found that there is more fun to lie
          had !.v Koing through the oldtitne Hal
          lowe'en rites quite ueriously when the
          party is small, while for a large affair
          this sort of diversion is hardly sufficiently!
          general, and instead there is dancing, pair
          sihly Hallowe'en cotillon and a supperj
          with quaint and grotesque favors.
          Masquerade parties are also popular for
          Hallowe'en, especially in girls' boarding
          schools, and afford r.o end of fun if the
          masks are kept on until the close of the
          evening, so that the identity of the
          dancers cannot he positively known.
          There are so many Hallowe'en symbols;
          that whether an ordinary dance, a cotillon
          or a masquerade is being arranged there
          is abundance of picturesque material upon'
          which one can draw for decorative ma
          terials, favurs, costumes, &c. No Hal-:
          lnwe'en masque is complete without its! 1
          witch, its jack-o'-lantern, black cat, owl
          and bat, nil to be represented in some way
          or other by the men or girls taking part.
          Brownies are also Hallowe'en characters.
          Goblins and fairies of all kinds are suita
          ble guests for a Hallowe'en frolic.
          IV/1 OST successful was a Hallowe'en'
          1 (masquerade given ut a girls' school i
          last year. Fairyland wus boldly!
          raided for the characters, and every girl j
          was asked to come as some one of "the
          little people," either as a historical char
          acter or as some particular sort of a I
          sprite. The result was not only most
          amusing but beautiful as well, for there
          were elves and pixies, water sprites, tire
          fairies, cloud fairies, quaint gnomes,
          naughty brownies, sharp chinned witches,
          &c. Queen Mali. Oberon, Titania and
          Turk were all there, and there was a
          most charming dryad, who set up her!
          How to Make a Motoring Veil
          EYEKY one has a motoring veil, and
          many and varied aye the kinds used.
          Few women or girls can be said to
          look really pretty in one of these veils,
          but there are many degreee of attractive-
          Beu about them, and still greater differ
          ences of convenience, which, after all, is I
          the really important point. Some are I
          merely long pieces of chiffon tied on in
          liny way, iind they frequently blow off
          in a high wind, so it is really worth while
          to make one properly.
          An English motoring veil which is i
          satisfactory is made in the following
          way:- Buy two yards of chiffon or chiffon
          cloth and cut it in half lengthwise from
          one ,-nd in a point twenty inches from
          the other end. Hem it across the two
          pieces of the loner end and all around
          the cut edges; the outer edges will, of
          course, lie selvages. Then, where the slit!'
          stops, it must Be closely buttonholed to
          pn >*nt tearing further.
          The upper end may be arranged in two|
          nis. .Lho simplest and easiest is to j'
          r it up lightly, sewing the gathers
          together at the edges; then sew over the
          g.i thers a large Hat button mould covered
          with the chiffon. A rather neater linflatter way to finish this top is with a j
          small thick ring, but it is mow trouble.!;
          In this case the chiffon must be turned
          over the ring like a hem and sewed down, r
          ;iinl as the whole width of chiffon must i
          be .sewed on a small ring it is not very i
          easy to do. Tho effect, however, is worth
          the trouble if one has some skill in
          sewing,
          Tho veil 1h put on with this gathered i
          centre near the front of the hat (or head j
          if worn without a hat), The beginning
          of tin- ,-lii i s ;ii the back of the neck, i
          and the two ends are. drawn around thejl
          tree in a corner— it was made of paper
          bark emerged at intervals through
          a cunningly concealed door.
          The witches told wonderful fortunes
          for everybody, and a large witch, who
          occupied a central post, stirred a cauldron
          from which she continually distributed
          favors.
          The gnomes «nd brownies roasted the
          chestnuts on the large hearth, and the I
          fairies danced around their favorite
          teacher and presented her with three
          magical gifts— Italian coral to keep
          off the evil eye, a good luck penny us a
          foundation for her fortune and a pair of
          rose colored glasses, through which she
          might always see the bright side of life.
          These fairies were not the ordinary
          tarletan and spangled creatures that we
          have grown accustomed to hear desig
          nated by that name, but were, as far as
          possible, faithful reproductions of the
          little people of famous fictiou, the creat
          ures of the Irish woods and bogs, the
          Scotch Highlands and the German forests
          as they have been depicted by poets,
          painters and prose writers. It took some
          trouble to evolve the costumes, but not
          as much expense as might be thought on
          first consideration, for many of the cos
          tumes were made entirely of crepe paper,
          and in all of them this material entered j
          largely.
          Black paper was most effective for the!
          witch's costume and for that of the owl
          and black cat Poor pussy had quite a
          difficult time —one of the smaller girls was j
          chosen for this —because the other
          guests at the frolic insisted on her going
          on all fours a large part of the time,
          which, in spite of her gymnastic training,
          was not altogether agreeable.
          EQUALLY amusing is a dance where
          the guests (ill appear as fruits of the)
          autumn. There must of course be
          some liberty permitted in this sort of
          character costuming, for while it is com»
          paratively easy for a properly built young
          person to appear as an ear of corn,
          it is rather diflicult for her or him to
          assume the exact proportions of a toma
          to. A lettuce girl, with full shaded green
          skirts of crinkled paper and some grace
          fully arranged lettuce leaves for bodice
          and headdress, is a most fascinating
          creature, and the grape costume, the au
          tiimn leaf costume, the pumpkin vine cos
          tume, &c, are all most attractive. It is
          usually considered wise for the girl to
          select fruit and vegetable costumes which
          are pretty and becoming, while the boys,
          with their customary gallantry, volunteer
          fur the grotesque parts.
          Squashes, radishes, potatoes and ap
          ples all fall to the lot of the boys. With
          the vegetable throng there should min
          gle a sufficient sprinkling of the tradi
          tional Hallowe'en characters. Nothing!
          could be more amusing than the pairing!
          off at such an assemblage. .Miss Lettuce
          and jack-o'-lantern dancing together, fol
          lowed by the witcli and the tomato boy, I
          thi; grape girl and the owl. picturesque 1
          Miss Autumn Leaf nn«l a jolly brownie,
          make up a procession of quaint contrasts.
          Pumpkin vines and autumn leaves are
          charming celebrations for large rooms in j
          which Hallowe'en frolics are to be held, j
          and thero are also paper draperies j
          stamped with appropriate designs which*
          come especially for the walls and tables.!
          Large witches' black cats and owls made
          of black paper are used here and there
          among the decorations or perched on
          chandeliers, lump shades or over door
          ways, Jaek-o'-lunterns, real or imita
          tion, are the most popular lights for the j
          festivities. If real they may be set ou i
          the table or hung in different quarters of
          neck, knotted in front and allowed to
          bang dowu, or put arouud the neck v
          second time when a little .extra warmth
          ia needed.
          Vegetale Embroidery.
          AVKKY prettj kind of fancy work
          is tin) vcgC'talo embroidery that is
          now one o£ the most tashionublej
          styles of trimming for dresses. It is easy
          to do and goes very quickly. A girl with
          only a little time to spend on embroidery
          can very soon make a lovely triminiug
          for her next new gown, be it one to weur
          to a dance or a cloth one for the street.
          For a little of the vcan be used on almost any kind of gown.
          It is made either in straight strips like
          an insertion or in the brassiere shape, i
          A young girl's evening gown in some soft
          white material, with a brassiere of vc'yu
          tale embroidery in white and gold, is so
          charming that it will pay any girl to do
          the embroidery. But if she doesn't want
          to do quite »'o much work 1 one little strip
          of it will add tremendously to the beauty
          of the dress.
          The work is done on net with very
          heavy I silk. When the gold effect is
          wanted either the gold tinsel thread may
          be used or a gold colored silk. The latter
          gives about as good an effect and ia
          softer. The patterns used are either
          conventionalized flowers or geometrical
          ligurcs, and they may be either stamped
          <>i> the net or on a heavy muslin or card
          hoard, over which the net is closely
          basted. It is rather easier to do it with
          the net basted on some stiff material, for
          that keeps it from polling up with the
          embroidery stitches, ,but it must be firmly
          fastened before the embroidery is begun.
          Kvi-ii if 011% prefers to have the pattern
          •tamped on the lift it is better not to try
          t<> do the embroidery with the stiff
          backing. I
          Los Angeles Sunday Herald
          THE WITCH'S HOUR
          GAMESkFOR YOUNG GIRLS' HALLOWE'EN PARTIES—ATTRACTIVE NOVELTIES
          j£ IN FAVORS AND DECORATIONS
          The Grcwsome Hallowe'en Owl
          the room. The imitation ones are in the
          form of lanterns, lamp shades and can
          dle shades.
          aI.L the fruits, vegetable* and nuts
          lire used fur Hallowe'en decorations.
          Brunches from nut trees with th«
          nuts still on are the motif of some of
          the draperies to bft v found in puper, and
          corn stalks, tree bark, &c, are all cou
          sidered suitable. For favors there are a
          great number of fascination boxes, bus
          |kets and bundles contliaiug bonbons, and
          there are ice cups also in a great variety
          of designs that are attractive and novel.
          Among the favors which are to be tilled
          with bonbons there are quaint little brown
          baskets with vegetables of different sorts
          on the lid, all »ortn of fruits and vege
          tables, with many small pumpkins espe-
          Icially noticeable, witches riding hroom
          ijsticks gayly attired in red and blaclt, and
          brown witches' brooms, the broom part
          lof which lifts off, disclosing the box. (hi.'
          lof the most attractive designs for the ice
          cups is a small lilt wheelbarrow tilled
          I with vegetable! of nfciny colon, among
          1 which the ice cup itself is ndroitly eon
          cealea.
          I There we also cups held up by three
          pars of corn or three rtdilbes or any of
          the tall thin vegetables. There are very
          pretty place cards made with little vege
          table* tied up in one comel 1 and Koine
          perfectly charming opes have endearing
          V)lack kittens fastened up in the corner
          with a bit of yellow ribbon, due of. the
          i and fkimiest favors is the lettuce
          land pumpkin boy, who has a lettuce body
          and a pumpkin head, nil made of paper,,
          «ud a curly green queue made of wirej
          twisted with green paper.
          Oldtime Hallowe'en rites include the
          mirror gazing, the burning of chestnuts,
          apple paring, carrying the candle and.
          cutting the Hallowe'en cake. There- are j
          also bobbing tat apple* and the game of,
          biting the apple, which, however, are not|
          uecesisarily Hallowe'en sports.
          Mirror gnzing must take place at mid
          night. The person who Is performing the
          rit.> must be quite alone in the room,
          which should be dark except for the
          candle she holds. She eats an apple and
          looks straight in the minor v the clock
          strikes twelve. She is rewarded by seeing
          her future husband's face In the mirror.
          The other method of prhrtising Hallow
          e'en mirror gazing requires even more
          courage. The eirl tnkesi her cnmllo and
          a small hafid mirror and goes alone down
          the cellar steps. At the mystic hour she
          nlso sees her future husband's fnc».
          BURNINU or roasting chestnuts on
          the hearth is a tried old custom. The
          girl names a chestnut for herself
          and one for the young man she supposes j
          may probably be her future fate. The
          nuts are then placed side by side on
          the hearth. If they bum quietly away
          together it is prophetic of a nappy mar
          riage. If they pop away from each other
          it is a sign that they will not be happy
          with each other. Whichever one pops
          away first is the least devoted.
          Apple paring—and paring is rather ililli
          ciili. An apple whieli has a (smooth skin
          should be selected and a large one is best.
          The Pumpkin and Lettuce Boys on Parade
          It must he evenly pared, so that the skin
          holds together and is about the same width.
          When finished the paring Is taken by one
          SOCIAL AMENITIES FOR
          THE SCHOOL GIRL
          AIIAI'IT of punctuality —ill do moiei
          to win popularity and will bring in
          its piith more tim and pleasure than
          nny other one characteristic Once a
          giri is known to 1"' unpsineluiil she
          will be left out of many v tpree arranged
          job the spur of iiio inoiiii-iit and requiring
          lii n lortuntaqeom itart "Oh, no, there I
          is DO use in asking Anna, she would ill- I
          ways keep us Waiting ll&d make us miss
          [Melng 10 much"—how often one hoars
          I that in connection with a contemplated
          [trip. Tlic sail part of it, 100, is that if
          [only poor Anna heard it she would un
          doubtedly promise to l>f *-ry good and by
          ready well on time for everything if only!
          she might be allowed to go. But her
          linbit« ure wull kuowu and ull feel they!
          cannot risk spoiling the pleasure of. an
          cm ire party just for her, so Home one
          else is diked instead, some one who, per
          haps, for many reasons will not make
          no congenial a companion, but who never
          theless has long ago discovered that one
          of the most sellish beings in existence.
          is mi uiipuix'tunl person and who has in;
          consequence herself formed the habit of
          always being on time.
          And continued unpunetimlity does re-1
          solve itself Into just that -selfishness, rtiej
          girl who is willing to keep a whole lunch
          eon party wailing hungrily and her hostess,
          nervously while she calmly prinks at
          I home, or does not stop what fine lihh been
          (loin;; in time to dress herself and get lo
          her entertaiMMOt, is certainly thinking ot
          herself before any one else.
          It is far better to waste a little time in
          waiting for an appointment than to keep
          another waiting who perhaps can ill
          ■ifford ihe extra momonU in a busy day.
          And then tliink of the possibilities of
          trouble that can be mimed by one girl
          being somewhat late, say, for some moru-
          i end and tossed over the shoulder. As it
          falls on the floor it may form a letter.
          i| If so, this is the first letter of the Ghris-
          ling appointment, be it only at the dress
          maker's. Because she is just a little be
          jhind time the next appointment must be
          put back somewhat, and perhaps the
          next person to be fitted is a business
          woman to whom time means actual
          money, or who ha* an important meeting
          herself immediately. She In turn must
          keep other* waiting; those others again
          have their day disarranged, and so on
          indefinitely until the proverbial pebble
          throws into a pond Bending out its ripples
          (o the shoto is but a small thing in com
          parison.
          Then therf fire tlir llok people to whom
          live or ten minutes' wailing means nn
          Interminable time and perhaps will bring'
          on a serious attaKk of nervousness. It isj
          far, far better not to set any exact timei
          for a citll with tut invalid than to stiitcl
          positively an hour that it is impossible
          to keep.
          That the ever increasing uupunctuality
          among American girls and women is to
          be attributed to the too busy, too full lit*
          which they lend Is true, but for this,
          very reason a girl cannot commence too|
          young to make up her mind firmly Unit
          she at least shall be known as reliable!
          aud able to carry out all that she mayi
          promise fo do nt a given time. It will I
          probably mean giving up some few pleas
          ures that others may not be incoiiveu
          iein-ed, but more than anything else ill
          means' starting in time to get ready.
          Whether it be for school or to meet n
          girl friend and take a walk, or for a din
          ner party, suine nne is sure to be incon
          venienced if, one is only a few moments
          lardy, while a difference of five or ten
          minutes at the other end in commencing
          to get ready Is nil that is necessary to
          avert this. Five minutes' extra sleep In
          the morning is of no benefit certainly,
          et nil' 1 person late nnd hurried at the
          breakfast table ''an upset the day for au
          entire household, family and servants
          tlan name of one'a future husband or
          wife.
          Carrying the oamlle should tnkc plaeo
          ontsirlc the hoilse. This would of course
          be difficult in n city, but in the country or
          suburbs could easily be managed. Each
          piicst is supplied with a candle, which is
          righted, and they start around the house
          In two procession^, the boys on one side,
          Hip girls on the other. If they fret back
          to the point from which they sttrted with
          out having the candles go out they are
          syrc to be married.
          At small or informal Hallowe'en nf
          fairs the supper provided usually iaoludes
          sandwiches, nuts, fruits, cider naff the
          Hallowe'en cake. If (he nffair In more
          elaborate salads and ices may b« added.
          Hallowe'en revels am apt to be late and
          the repast should be rather substantial.
          Salads made of apples or nuts are par
          ticularly suitable and the ices should be
          in the form of applFor the more simple Hallowe'en banquet
          it is amusing to have plafn enkes, ginser
          cake and cookies, cut in Hallowe'en shapes.

        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 10 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1914-10-31/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=HALLOWEEN+Halloween+HALLOWE%27EN+Hallowe%27en+celebrate+celebration&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.222,-0.072,1.445,1.445,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          EVENING LEDGER-PHILADELPHIA-, SATURDAY, OCTOBER SI. 10X3
          FRIVOLOUS FOLLIES AND FANCIES FANTASTIC THAT FASCINATE HALLOWEEN'S MAID
          SUGGESTIONS FOR HALLOWEEN COSTUMES
          FAIRIES' HALLOWEEN PARTY
          HALLOWEEN ENTERTAINMENT
          ww
          Cm I ill r
          .H
          U i
          'SL
          41

          ,r r
          i 'i
          lib lii
          The Halloween fairies were giving a
          part jr. Tliero was the pumpkin fairy, In
          shimmering shining yellow; tho apple
          fairy In russet nnd green, tho nut fairies
          In golden browns, and many others Into
          the bargain.
          They wer giving their party In ,the
          hollow of a great big oak tree. The
          friendly fireflies had offered to furnish
          the Illumination, and so many of thorn
          came that there wasn't the least bit of
          danger that their lights would all go out
          at the same time, and If they had there
          were several stow-worms that were more
          than willing to shine steadily right
          through the evening
          Outside, on a low branch of the tree, a
          Undly old owl mounted guard. If any
          of the mischievous goblins or hobgoblins
          ventured near he meant to warn the
          fairies by calling out "To-whool to
          whool" In plenty of time for them to
          mako their oscapo
          Locusts and katydids had been Invited
          to supply tho music Thoy sang over
          nnd over again to the delight of every
          one present And for refreshments they
          had little acorn cups Ailed with delicious
          dew caught that very morning and tiny
          ooJtes of honey made especially for the
          occasion by tho bora who had their hives
          nearby and who sent them with theli
          compliments.
          The fairies made a fairy ring and
          danced around It while the locusts and
          katydids sang their best songs, and the
          glow-worms and the fireflies made the
          Inside of the big tree brilliant with their
          yellow lights.
          The youngest fairies served the refresh
          ments, not forgetting a single llreflv or
          glow-worm or locust or katydid, and tho
          older fairies sat together on little chains
          made of lovely pink and yellow toad
          stools. The pumpkin fairy told of her busy,
          busy tlmo, flying around and touching
          MM I B 11 u
          The Origin of Halloween
          The only mysterious festival left to
          prosaic Americans Is Halloween. Its
          origin is plainly Pagan, although the ro
          mantic element has come to us from
          England, Ireland and Scotland
          Around the 1st of November the Druids
          were supposed to hold their worship of
          the sun god, thanking him for the har
          vest. Huge sacrificial fires were TTghted
          In his honor, and kept lighted for days
          This Influence can still be seen in the
          "bonfire night" In Ireland.
          The Roman conquerors penetrated as
          far as Britain, and from them comes the
          custom of using nuts and apples on Hal
          loween. On this night Soman, the lord
          of death, was believed to call together
          all the souls of the wicked. These were
          condemned to Inhabit the bodies of
          beasts for a year, and Halloween marks
          their release.
          This fact or belief perhaps, marks
          the predominance of the mysterious ele
          ment In Halloween frolics. It Is the
          night when witches, elves and evl!
          spirits walk abroad They sour the
          cream, tie cats' talis together and per
          form the thousand and one pranks
          usually attributed to small boys
          Robert Burns In his poem, "Halloween,"
          gives us a good description of the ways
          employed to penetrate the veil of the
          future. Three nuts are placed on the
          hearth. Each Is named after a. lover.
          If one cracks, he will be unfaithful.
          If one burns, ha will be faithful, etc.
          llany maidens ate an npple slowly before
          a. looking-glass. The face of her future
          husband was supposed to peep over her
          boulder.
          Children bom on Halloween are sup
          posed to have the power to perceive and
          communicate -with spirits. Sir Walter
          Beott makes use of this in his romance,
          "The Monastery."
          Ordeal of tho Lighted Candle

          A lighted candle
          should be placed in
          the middle of the
          .room, and each guest
          should be blindfolded
          and told to Jump
          over It Those who
          clear it without ex
          tinguishing the flame
          I will have a happy
          and prosperous year
          ahead, but those who
          fail in clear it. or
          who lenock It over, will be very unlucky
          for the next twelvemonth!
          The Needle-threading Test
          It is very hard to thread a needle when
          seated on a round bottle laid lengthwise
          on the floor. It will roll about In the
          most surprising fashion The one who
          succeeds in threading the needle first will
          be the first to get married.
          Around the Apple Tub
          No Halloween par
          ty is complete with
          out the large tub
          filled with cold wa
          ter. Its surface
          crowded with the
          reddest of rosy
          cheeked apples Borne
          one should be se
          lected as manager of
          the sports, as guests.
          In their excitement.
          need to be regulated
          and controlled, or
          they may tumble
          headlong into the tub'
          A line should be formed, and each
          should kneel in turn end bob or duck
          their beads down Into the water, trying
          to secure an apple with the Weih. Fre
          quently the resisting apple has to be
          pursued to the wwy bottom of the tub,
          but this makes the game all the mora
          exciting, although the clothes are apt to
          get utterly soaked.
          To prevent this, the wise hostess will
          lay In a stock of water-proof bibs for the
          girts. wY'ja the men shgjld remove col
          Lars, tks and coats.
          -sns
          Afe
          3
          each eeparato pumpkin with her wnnd so
          that It would grow big and golden, and of
          n luscious flavor.
          The grape nnd poach and pear and apple
          fairies all had good reports to give of
          all their fruit trees, and the llttlo nut
          fairies said that they had not only pro
          vided enough nuts for every child and
          grown-up person for miles around, but
          they had made sure of a supply for all
          tho llttlo furrv, brlpht-eyed squirrels and
          chlpmunM that would last nil winter
          They were drinking each other's healths
          In tho little ncorn cups of bramble dew
          when suddenly To-whoo' called tho big
          eld owl, and they alt caught their breaths
          and stood perfectly still, oh, so terribly
          frightened'
          To-whool To-whoo' sang the owl, and
          each tlmo much louder than before.
          Tho Inside of the tree trunks, that look
          ed so pretty, festooned with fairy lcaes
          and How era and grasses nnd mosses, sud
          denly became pitch black Tho glow
          worms stopped glowing and tho lights
          of the flrouies all went out at the ery
          eame Instant
          Fairies and fireflies and glow-worms, lo
          custs and katydids flew all mixed up to
          gether, up and up, right up through tfce
          tree trunk until they reached the top.
          Then out they flew and away and away,
          under tho cover of the leaves until they
          were all safely home and ervery single
          one of them tucked In bed
          And the mischievous llttl sprites and
          goblins and hobgoblins that had come
          stealing up tho tree Just to frighten the
          fairies found nothing nt alt.
          They peered Into the big hollow of the
          oak tree, but there were no friendly fire
          flies and glow-worms to light It up for
          them, so they turned away quite de
          jected and maybo a little bit ashamed.
          Tho wise old owl kept one eye cocked
          open until the last one had vanished.
          Then he ruffled up his feathers, tucked
          his head under his wing and went to
          sleep for the night.
          Hallowe'en in Frolics
          Pretty games belong to Halloween more
          particularly than nny other time of the
          year. Certainly, no other feast offers
          such a variety of them Every country
          lends it epecullar customs, for Halloween
          is countless centuries old.
          "Ships of Fate" Is perhaps the prettiest
          and most romantic game of all Little
          ships are made of half an English walnut
          shell, -with little toothpick masts secured
          to the bottom of the shell with candle
          grease. The name of each guest Is
          printed or written on each boat. A little
          lighted candle Is placed In the stern
          Place these In a tub of water and fan
          gently. Much amusement follows the
          gradual pairing off of the boats Tho
          candle, of course, typifies good health
          Whoever has the candle which burns tho
          longest may expect a long and happy
          life. The boats may bo Improved upon
          In countless -ways and look very attractive
          with the lights shining In the water.
          A new version of the old custom of
          bobbing for apples Is, perhaps, not so
          exciting, but decidedly more reassuring
          for the unfortunate victims who have to
          go home on a cold night with wet cloth
          ing. The apples are placed in a row,
          using green, yellow and red ones al
          ternately. The guests are supplies with
          darts, or tiny bows and arrows. Shoot
          ing a red apple signifies success In love,
          a yellow one, money, and the green one
          health.
          An old English custom Is that of hang
          ing a stick parallel to the celling by a
          strong cord. On one end of this Is stuck
          a large lighted candle, on the other an
          apple. The stick Is then spun around
          rapidly, and the guests are supposed to
          secure a bite of the apple The pleasure
          of this game Is very doubtful.
          Slarshmellow toasting, roasting chest
          nuts, apples, pop-corn, new corn and
          Buch things before the open Are are less
          strenuous and still popular amusements
          for Halloween.
          The Boasting of Chestnuts
          The true lovers' test Is found In the
          roasting of chestnuts. A young man and
          a girl should each place a chestnut on
          the bars of the grate and carefully watch
          their behavior. If they stay quietly side
          by Bide, then the young couple who
          placed them there will lead an easy,
          peaceful life together But If, as Is fre
          quently the case, the nuts hiss and steam,
          then such behavior Indicates quarreling
          between tho owners. Frequently one
          chestnut will act In a wild manner, Jump
          Irg away from the other and hlBslng
          loudly, and this Indicates that the owner
          has a bad temperl
          The Halssin 1la.ee
          Into a piece of string about a yard long
          a raisin Is strung. Two people then take
          each an end in their mouths and hastily
          chew as much as possible. The one who
          reaches the raisin first will be wedded
          first.
          Recipe for Halloween
          Peanut Candy
          For a thick peanut candy boll together
          a cupful of sugar, a cupful of molast.es
          and two tablespoonfuls of butter ery
          slowly for about half an hour Then
          try In cold water and when It Is brittle
          add a cupful of shelled peanuts Pour
          Into well greased pans to the depth of
          half an Inch When It begins to harden
          cut Into squares with a buttersd knife.
          A crisp peanut candy that is easily
          made Is made by melting and browning
          granulated sugar, being careful that it
          does not burn, and then pouring It, when
          it Is all melted and brown, over shelled
          peanuts. When It is cold break It In
          pieces.
          Barley Omelettes
          Break two eggs Into a basin, remove
          the specks and beat well (If at hand,
          throw in a spoonful of minced parsley),
          a dust of pepper and salt It for savory
          one. If a swet one, add sugar Stir into
          the beaten eggs enough boiled barley to
          make It the thickness of a rich batter,
          then form It Into thin cakes with floured
          Angers Lay them Into a pan of heated
          fat; turn or hold before a bright are
          Minted onions may be added if ap
          proved. The omelette should be lifted
          w th a spoon or knife to prevent it stick
          ing to the pan. which It will do if it is
          a weil-used pan Take to table as sgon
          as choked Jam or stewed fruit may be
          used with this omelette.
          IDEAS FOR
          Halloween Is a time of rejoicing and
          festivity, and many delightful parties aie
          given to celebrate it fittingly The prob
          lem of entertaining the guests harasses
          many a hostess, and for her assistance
          tho following time-honored games are re
          corded: First In tho list comes snapdragon. This
          game Is a great favorite with the younger
          folks, and even the elders will enjoy It.
          About half a pint of brandy should be
          put Into a dish and a match applied to
          It. The moment It catches fire tho light
          In the room should be put out, so that
          the sole Uluminntlon comes from the blaz
          ing brandy.
          Handfuls of candled fruits, raisins,
          sugared almonds are then flung In. and
          the guests must try to snatch them out
          of tho flames. This causes great excite
          ment and much laughter, and Is sure to
          make the party a success The girl or
          man who manages to obtain the highest
          amount of fruit, etc from the flames
          will meet her, or his, future mato within
          a year!
          Another delightful
          game is played with
          a mirror. The moon
          should be shining
          brightly, and the
          guest must walk sev
          everal paces back
          ward In the moon
          light, holding a looking-glass
          In one hand
          and gazing all the
          time Into the looking-glass.
          If the fol
          lowing verse is re
          peated, the face of
          the guest's future
          husband or wife, as
          the case may be, will
          appear In the glass:
          "Round and round, O itars so falrl
          Ye travel an1 eeareh cut eo where;
          I Tray ou. sweet stars, row show to me
          Thie night who my future husband (or
          wlfoj will te!"
          The Shadow Game
          This is a splendid
          game for Halloween
          A sheet or tablecloth
          KhnuM hfk Htratchecl
          across the centre ofl'l
          the room and a lamp
          placed behind It on
          u table. The lights
          in the room are then
          put out. and one
          player fits at the side between the lamp
          and the sheet The other players
          must then pass In turn behind the one
          sitting on the stool, their shadows being
          thrown upon the sheet They make all
          sorts of contortions and grimaces, wear
          false noses and beards, etc, and the
          man on the stool must try to guess their
          identity This Is a rather difficult proposl.
          tlon as the shadows seem strangely dis
          torted and twisted
          An Old English Halloween Custom
          The girl or man who is anxious to Know
          who her or his future companion for life
          will be will steal out on the night of
          Halloween quite alone, and will pluck a
          hair out of the head and cast It away,
          watching carefully In which direction the
          breeze may blow it The future partner
          will live in the direction In which the
          hair blows To make the charm work,
          the following verse should be recited
          aloud:
          "I pluck this leek of hair off my head
          Tu tell wboBie com the one I shall wed.
          Fly. allken tulr, Oy all the world around
          Until ou rwua the spot wlwre my truu lovt
          U found."
          Another game that will cause great In
          terest among the guests is played in this
          fashion: Take three dishes, rill one with
          clear water, the tecond with wattr Into
          which some black ink has been poured,
          and leave the third dish empty One of,
          the guests is then blindfolded and led
          to the table where the three dlsheu are
          laid The guest then dips his (or her) left
          forefinger Into one of the dishes. If it
          is the empty dish he Is fated to be a
          bachelor all his life or, if the player
          oe a lady, sho wid be an old maid If
          tuo flnser Is dipped Into the Inky water
          szm
          IMi
          A HALLOWE'EN PARTY 3S&
          the player wll marry a widow of a
          widower, but if the finger is dipped into
          tho clear water, then the future partner
          for llfo will be young, charming and
          handsome
          A ory amusing game Is played with
          mashed potatoes. Into tho midst of the
          mashed potatoes a dime, a ring and a
          thimble should ba placed. The potatoes
          are then eaten by the guests, nnd great
          Is the excitement n to who will got the
          articles burled In the mashed potatoes.
          Tho one who gets tho ring will soon bo
          married. The ono who gets tho thimble
          will live alono all his or her llfo. The
          discovery of the dime betokens tho re
          ception of a legacy or the gaining of
          riches
          A eplcndld way of entertaining the
          guests Is the hiding of nuts or apples in
          different places In the room. Several
          people should then be blindfolded, and
          they must hunt around for the hidden
          articles Hostesses who valuo their fur
          nlturo and ornaments, etc wil start this
          bolbtorous game at their own risk.
          An amusing game Is tho trial by water.
          The gueet must fill his mouth with water
          and walk nround tho house without swnl
          lowlng or losing a drop of It. The first
          person met of the opposite sex will bo
          his fate. The Idea Is to send two young
          people out by different doors. If the
          young people selected are at all friendly,
          the fun will wax fast and furious, and as
          they are sure to meet, this simple game
          may bring matters to a crisis.
          Apple-Paring Test
          A third and most popular Halloween
          game Is played with applesklns. The
          npple should be pared, care being taken to
          do so In one long, unbroken piece. The
          paring should then be swung around the
          head, flung over the left shoulder and
          allowed to drop on the floor The letter
          thus farmed will show the Initial of Uie
          thrower's future mate for life.
          The Fun of Forfeits
          No Halloween party Is complete without
          the forfeit toll. When a player Is fined
          for the breach of some rule or for some
          mistake In a game, or for being defeated
          In some test, he must at once surrender
          a piece of his private property, such as
          a stud, or. In the case of a girl, a bracelet
          ur biooch or something of the sort
          A ready-witted person is then chosen to
          play the part of the Justice. There Is
          also a collector, who holds out the arti
          cle forfeited, crying, "Who Is the owner
          of this pretty thing?" The owner then
          comes forward, kneels down at the feet
          of Justice and Is told what he must do
          to redeem the goods. The penalties are
          varied and amusing:
          "Leave the room with two legs and
          come back with six The way to do this
          13 to go out Of the room and return carry
          ing a chair
          "Place one hand where the other cannot
          pet at it." The way to do this is to grasp
          the elbow.
          The quick-witted Justice will Invent
          many amusing penalties, and the game of
          forfeits will proceed in a very lively
          manner.
          Fortune Telling on Halloween
          One of the party
          should dress up as a
          witch or gipsy and
          tell the fortunes of
          the rest of the com
          pany Another method Is
          to write the for
          tunes on small pieces
          of white paper, us
          ing milk Instead of
          Ink. and when dry,
          place the slips In
          mn.v wolnn, el, Alia
          V.l.f.J H..V..W.
          JJ The shells can then
          T7 be sealed up, all
          captaole, and each guest now selects one
          On opening the walnut shells, the paper
          should be taken out and heated a little,
          when the milk will turn slightly brown
          and the writing be clearly revealed
          Great surprise will be caused at thus see
          jesT the fortune llteraiy grow Into vUnr
          Ir
          I
          All Halloween
          This is the nlcht o Hallowe'en,
          When a" the wlchtln mlcht o seen;
          Boms o them black, eome o them green,
          Some o' them llko a turkey Dean.
          Feast days and fast days, holidays and
          festivals come and go, but Halloween
          Is unique. It Is vested with the charm
          of all that there Is of the mystical, the
          strango and the weird and the super
          natural. Evil spirits hold high carnival, witches
          ride the air, goblins and hobgoblins,
          fairies and elves appear boldly, and the
          souls of the dead come forth from their
          graves and roam the earth.
          Even Us origin Is mysterious, pagan
          and Christian with a .dash of the
          mythological thrown In, perhaps. Long
          ago a feast was held in honor of Pomona,
          goddess of tho harvest. In England the
          Druids held a harvest celebration nt this
          time of year and built great bonfires
          In high places in honor of the sun
          that ripened their grain. In the Cath
          olic calendar the Eve of All Saints
          coincided with the pagan festival and
          became Involved In the fantastic rites
          of the earlier celebration.
          It Is a night when It Is not safr to
          be out in the dark and alone, a night
          when any man or maiden has the right
          and the might to invoke the spirit of
          tho future spouse by strange spells and
          Incantations. Faith In maslo Is all that
          Is needed.
          And It Is a night, flrs.t and last and
          all tho time, when grown-up pooplo can
          cast aside the affairs of state, the pomp
          of circumstance, and be what thoy would
          most like to be la all the world merry
          hearted children.
          And If we no longer really and truly
          believe In the supernatural, there Is a
          remembrance of the belief to serve the
          purpose and a wish that la almost a
          faith In Its power
          In a word, Halloween Is romance, the
          Never-Never Land that we are all seek
          ing, Bometlmes unknowingly and some
          times with the dusty highway of tho
          commonplace stretching ahead of us In
          terminably, and blinding our eyes.
          The Rose Test, for Girls
          Choose one for yourself and one for
          jour lover.
          This requires two roses with long stems.
          American Beauties are splendid foi this
          purpose You must try the test in soli
          tude, preferably in your own room. Vou
          must kneel down, fix your eyes on the
          rose chosen for your lover, twine the
          stems of the two flowers together and re
          peat the following aloud:
          "Twine, twine and
          Intertwine,
          Let my love be
          wholly thine.
          If his heart be kind
          and true,
          Deeper grow his
          rose's hue
          If your lover loves
          jou truly, the rose
          should grow deeper
          in color.
          The Mirror Test
          You must stand
          alone before a mir
          ror and comb jour
          hair by candlelight.
          A single candle
          snould re usea ior
          this occasion You will then see In the
          clflttn iha tnrtk nf vnur future Ufa com
          panion
          wmwjiijwimiiiWiWimMimii
          Benj. B. Lewis
          DRESS PLEATING.
          HEMSTITCHING. PINKING
          AND GOFFERING
          BUTTONS COVERED
          Excellent tcorfc reasonable prices.
          1535 Chestnut Street
          Take Elevator
          ut.sr3taL.3
          In these days of apartment living one
          may have to beg, borrow or steal a cel
          lara modern cellar, of course, clean and
          dry, with n cement floor but certainty
          thero Is no place quite ltke It for a chil
          dren's Hallowe'en party. The descent to
          tho cellar of Itself puts ono In the proper
          anticipatory spirit! tho usual lioxllko
          stairway, dimply lighted, Is spooky just
          of Itself.
          A cellar, with grinning Jack o'Lan
          terns, giving an orange glow for tho only
          light; with autumn leaves and grasses
          festooned from the walls nnd celling; with
          witches, bats, cats nnd owls cut from
          black paper In nllhouotto and pasted
          against white walls, makes a picture In
          tuno with the weird and mysterious
          forces awake and abroad on this one
          night of tho year.
          A witch's caldron mndo of pasteboard,
          covered with black paper and set on a
          tripod, should bubble over with Hallow
          con favors. A bona fide witch, dressed
          with all the mummery of the part, should
          preside and distribute crackers, rattles
          and whistles to all bold enough to claim
          them.
          There aro games ns old as the hills
          that seem new overy year and never loso
          their charm. Bobbing for apples Is one,
          and a placo for a tub already filled with
          water should be found somewhere In tho
          picture. There should bo apples strung
          from tho colling that can be secured only
          by catching them with tho teeth. A
          table laden with nuts and fruits must
          Halloween Table Decoration
          Halloween offers unlimited opportunities
          for artistic tablo decorations. Autumn
          harmonics prevail, tho color schemes
          shown being chiefly orange, dcop reds
          and browns. Of course, tho weird black
          witches and white skeletons aro also In
          ovldence. One very charming table had
          a cloth mado of orange crepe paper, with
          a border of wltchos and cats In black.
          A good-sized houso made of black cropo
          paper pasted over cardboard formed tho
          centrepiece, and astrldo the roof sat a
          very formidable looking wltoh. Her body
          was made of a clothespin, with corn
          tassel hair, a realistically painted faco,
          and garments of shreddod orange and
          black paper. Tho lights used were can
          dles, and to got tho proper eerie atmos
          phero shades were made of dark
          grotesque faces, pumpkin heads and grin
          ning cats. Apples nnd other fruits wero
          ornamented by flags stuck In them, bear
          ing a Bkull and cross-bones. Quests are
          supplied with favors appropriate to tho
          occasion. Orange and black caps, faintly
          suggestlvo of the brownies, are vory pop
          ular. Tho whole effect Is very realistic,
          and from a hostess' point of view, vory
          successful.
          The "Walnut Treo
          "Lat Ilallow Eve I nought a walnut tree.
          In hopes my true love's face I might ee.
          Three times I called, threa times I walked
          apace:
          Then In tho tree I saw my true love's face."
          day
          If you wish to see
          the face of your fu
          ture husband (or
          wife) walk out In the
          moonlight on Hal
          loween to the near
          est walnut treo, walk
          around It three- times,
          calling out, "Let him
          that Is to be my
          true lovo bring me
          soma walnuts," and
          you will see your
          future husband (or
          wife) gathering them
          In the tree I
          The Halloween Card Party
          Auction Is the order of tho daj At
          every hour of the day, and mostly every
          hour of the night, a feverish bridge flend
          mny be seen looking for Its mato. The
          ever-popular tango is auction's only rival
          for popularity. This brings us to tho point
          of card players In general.
          You have all mot the charming little
          woman who has no thought on earth ex
          cept "dear John" and the children
          Ordinarily she Is most attractive, but In
          the serious mntter of brldgo you rattier
          lose your disposition when sho cheerfully
          doubles "Just to see what will happen"
          Such a partner is a grievous trial, but
          aay, with Cervantes, "Patience and shuttle
          the cards." To act annoyed at a partner's
          Ignorance of the game Is out of place; to
          criticize her play is Inexcusable.
          As for the giggly person, who cheer
          ftillj disregards alt her partner's signal
          bids, looks bored while her opponents
          play the dummy hand; in brief, who
          doesn't try at all, nothing Is too terrible
          She should either give cards up entirely
          or pay attention. That Is only fair to the
          other players
          Scientific "brldgers" have been blamed
          for their strict attention to the game This
          Is a very good fault, Those who play o
          game for tho love of It, and not for a
          pair of fancy ghnes or a camisole, can
          easily understand this. Nothing Is "so try
          Ing In any game as tho amateur Ilrldge
          etiquette Is a vei-y well defined thing und
          should be carefully observed by all
          players.
          On the whole. It Is the card player who
          always had a good time, whether he wins
          or loses; who takes defeat like success,
          with a bmlle, who plays carefully and
          wins occasionally: who is willing to help
          the beginner, and who never, never criti
          cizes, who is a favorite at bridge parties
          ties.
          Walnut Croquettes
          One cup bread crumbs. 1 cup milk, a;
          cup chopped walnuts, hi. teaspoon salt
          Cook the milk and crumbs to a paste,
          add walnuts, yolks of eggs and salt
          Shape Into balls, dip Into beaten egg and
          roll In crumbs. Fry In deep fat
          To Advertisers
          Send Copy in Early
          If you would secure insertion in the early
          mail edition of the Sunday Public Ledger have
          your advertisements at the Main Office or
          Ledger Central before 5 P. M. Saturdays.
          Telephone your Want Ads to
          Walnut or Main 3000
          have at least one cake-mold mads of
          flour.
          In It there must be a ring for the first
          ono t6 be married, a. thimble for th
          Bplnater or old bachelor and a piece of
          money for the lucky one. The flour li
          sliced with a knlfo like an ordinary cake
          and the person who makes a find with
          the knife can hare It only by bltlne u
          out with tho teeth.
          Phllopcna with forfeits Invented by
          tho children adds to the fun. Fortune,
          telling with nuts and apples Is one of
          the rites of tho evening not to be over
          looked. A supper table, If thero It
          supper, spread with a paper tablecloth
          stamped with Halloween devices, and
          with paper napkins Is much more attrac
          tive than It could ba with ordinary linen.
          Candlesticks can bo made from hollonej
          cucumbers, and a pumpkin filled with
          fruit seems right nnd fitting for the cen
          terpiece. Placo cards can be bought or
          made by fastening the Halloween stlcken
          to orange or scarlet cards. The In vita,
          tlons to the party should not be neglect,
          ed; It takes so little Imagination to make
          them amusing and Interesting.
          A Halloween party without costumes
          and masques is like an egg -without salt.
          They aro easily mado or can bo bought
          for a song. Spooks and sprites, gobllni
          and ghosts, It doesn't matter what th
          choice. It Is the dlsgulso that counts,
          Bouvenlrs, and thero should be souvenirs
          of tho party, to bo stowed away with
          other treasures, can bo bought In the
          Bhapo of n dlmlnutlvo lantern or candle,
          stick, or n small slab of chocolate, with
          ono of the sprites atendnnt on Halloween,
          cither bearing It or being borne upon 11
          The Needle Game
          Each guest should bo given a needle and
          a tiny piece of butter, so that the neaalt
          may be greased. The needles are then
          placed In a basin of water, each guest
          watching his or her own needle care
          fully. By tho low of magnetism and at
          traction the needle will rush apart or
          together, as the enso may be, and the
          manner In which each needlo behaves will
          betoken the actions and tho relationships
          of the parties concerned in the game.
          The Halloween Jinx
          Yes, surely you know about lt-the
          Halloween Jinx. It's only a theory, soma
          people say, but nevertheless awful things
          have been known to happen when you
          mado tho Jinx mad.
          You see, Halloween Is Buch a mysterious,
          eerie old night that tho elves and goblins
          and hobgoblins and whatnots all creep
          from their holes and peer around Well,
          If they should happen to see any kiddle
          or grown up, either with a frown on'
          A piercing shriek may be heard through
          out the house, and by this the unhappy
          "frowner" knows his fate. The "Jinx"
          Is on you for another j'car.
          So bo careful, kiddles, to smile and
          frolic, so that the Halowcen Jinx won't
          see you when he comes prowling around
          tonight.

        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
